good night everyone
おやすみなさい、皆さん
Lecture is about to start
いよいよ講義が始まります
Please set your phone to vibrate or silent
携帯電話を振動またはサイレントに設定してください
Remind you
思い出させます
This presentation is in progress
このプレゼンテーションは進行中です
Please wear a mask at all times
常にマスクを着用してください
and prohibit eating
そして食べることを禁止する
video and audio recording
ビデオとオーディオの記録
Do not use the flash when taking pictures
写真を撮るときはフラッシュを使用しないでください
Thank you for your cooperation
ご協力ありがとうございます
Academia Sinica's 112-year-old governor Cai Yuanpei's popular science award begins
中央研究院の蔡源培院長（112）の人気科学賞が始まる
We ask Vice President Zhou Meiyin to host for us
周美音副大統領に司会をお願いします
Ask Vice President Zhou Meiyin to host for us
周美音副大統領に司会を依頼してください
Dear teachers Ma, distinguished guests and colleagues, good night everyone
親愛なるマー先生、来賓の皆様、そして同僚の皆様、皆さんおやすみなさい
In order to commemorate the 155th birthday of President Cai Yuanpei Gu
蔡元培九総統の生誕155周年を記念して
So we are holding today this is the 2023 Governor's Vision
そこで私たちは今日、これが2023年の知事のビジョンであると考えています。
Dean Cai Yuanpei's Science Popularization Award
蔡元培学部長科学普及賞
So we are very happy and honored to invite you to the Institute of Earth Sciences
ですから、皆さんを地球科学研究所にご招待できることを大変うれしく光栄に思います。
Ma Guofeng Distinguished Researcher of the Institute of Earth Sciences
馬国鋒 地球科学研究所特別研究員
come and give us a lecture
来て私たちに講義をしてください
see this generation of light that initiates earthquakes
地震を引き起こすこの光の生成を見てください
When the light first penetrates into the monitoring of the fault zone
光が断層帯の監視に初めて侵入するとき
this could be very interesting
これはとても興味深いかもしれません
Then we know that Mr. Ma graduated from
その後、マー氏が卒業したことがわかりました。
Department of Geophysics, Chuo University
中央大学地球物理学科
Then at the Institute of Oceanography at National Taiwan University
その後、国立台湾大学海洋研究所へ
Study abroad after earning a master's degree
修士号取得後に留学
Finally at Caltech
ついにカリフォルニア工科大学へ
The Department of Geology and Planetary Sciences
地質惑星科学科
very special one
とても特別なもの
received a Ph.D.
博士号を取得しました
Return to Taiwan to serve after graduation
卒業後は台湾に戻って奉仕する
Then enter Central University to teach
その後、中央大学に入学して教鞭をとる
until 2020
2020年まで
Transfer to this institute as a special research institute of the Earth Institute
地球科学研究所の特別研究機関として当研究所に異動
He is also currently the Chief Scientist of the Taiwan Earthquake Science Center
彼は現在、台湾地震科学センターの主任研究員でもあります。
That's also the director of the Earthquake Disaster Chain Risk Assessment and Management Research Center at Chuo University
中央大学地震災害連鎖リスク評価・管理研究センター所長でもあります
Mr. Nama's main major is in seismology and political mechanics
ナマ先生の主な専攻は地震学と政治力学です。
So wait a minute to hear him explain this to us
それで、彼がこれについて私たちに説明するのを聞くまで少し待ってください
These studies are able to observe earthquakes that are very relevant to us
これらの研究により、私たちに非常に関係のある地震を観測することができます。
His greatest contribution was the first observation of the thickness of the Chinese belt of a large earthquake fault
彼の最大の貢献は、大地震断層の中国帯の厚さを初めて観測したことである。
Then, quantitative calculations can be used to obtain the energy for generating earthquakes
そして、地震を発生させるエネルギーを定量的に計算することができます。
then what energy
じゃあ何のエネルギー
military research on earthquakes, etc.
地震などに関する軍事研究。
We'll hear some research on this later
これについては後で調査結果を聞きます
What about the research on earthquake disaster risk assessment?
地震災害リスク評価の研究についてはどうですか？
We can take the results of academic research
学術研究の結果を取り入れることができます
applied to related industries
関連産業に適用される
To reduce the damage caused by earthquakes
地震による被害を軽減するために
So this is our Academia Sinica doing basic research
これが私たちの中央研究院で基礎研究を行っています
But it is closely related to the current situation of Paiwai.
しかし、それはパイワイの現状と密接に関係しています。
Teacher Nama Guofeng has received many academic honors
生国鋒教師は多くの学術的栄誉を獲得しています
as early as 2000
2000年にはすでに
Elected as one of the top ten outstanding young women of the Republic of China
中華民国の優秀な若い女性トップ10の一人に選出
In 2011, he won the Taiwan Outstanding Scientist Award
2011年に台湾優秀科学者賞を受賞
Received the 17th National Award from the Ministry of Education in 2013
2013年第17回国民教育大臣賞を受賞
Measure right as long as it doesn't matter
問題にならない限り正しく測定する
and many other awards
その他多くの賞を受賞
2019 was elected to the American Geophysical Union
2019年にアメリカ地球物理学連合の会員に選出されました
2021 is the Year of the Earth Science Society of Asia and Oceania
2021 年はアジア・オセアニア地球科学協会の年です
These awards of an X-Ware Medal Award
X-Ware メダル賞のこれらの賞
So now we're talking about today's lecture
それでは今日のことについて話しましょう
I will introduce this to you in particular
特にこれを紹介します
Our so-called vibration research on seismic waves observed by Mitsusen
光船が観測した地震波のいわゆる振動研究
can help us
私たちを助けることができます
The observation of this earthquake
今回の地震の観測
And then going deep into this fault zone can provide high-resolution seismic signals
そして、この断層帯の奥深くまで進むと、高解像度の地震信号が提供される可能性があります。
This is very important to our understanding of earthquakes
これは地震を理解する上で非常に重要です
Okay, now please give us a big round of applause
それでは、大きな拍手をお願いします
Welcome Ma Guofeng Distinguished Researcher
馬国鋒特別研究員を歓迎します
Give us a special lecture today
今日は特別講義をしてください
Thank you Vice President for your introduction
副社長、ご紹介ありがとうございました
Also, thank you, my friends, for your special attention.
また、友人の皆様、格別のご配慮を賜り、誠にありがとうございます。
Thanks
ありがとう
I am very happy to have this opportunity today
今日はこのような機会を頂けてとても嬉しいです
Personally, I think it is in our seismological science supernatural
個人的には、それは私たちの地震科学の超常現象にあると思います
very important for a new generation
新しい世代にとって非常に重要な
Then I think each science is about 20 to 30 years
そうすると、それぞれの科学には20年から30年くらいかかると思います
There will be a new conversion into
への新しい変換が行われます
then i'm glad to have this opportunity
それではこの機会を頂けて嬉しいです
when i was a doctor
私が医者だったとき
Seismology from flat to broadband
平面からブロードバンドまでの地震学
How about when you are more senior?
もっと先輩になったらどうでしょうか？
Having access to this highest resolution material again
この最高解像度の素材に再びアクセスできるようになりました
Analysis with the current big data data
現状のビッグデータデータを活用した分析
Earthquake Science Content
地震科学コンテンツ
then i'm happy too
それなら私も嬉しいです
My idea has achieved a key breakthrough in the hospital
私のアイデアは病院で重要な進歩を遂げました
support for this project
このプロジェクトへの支援
Only way to get this job today
今日この仕事に就く唯一の方法
Well, this is actually a new attempt
そうですね、これは実は新しい試みです
Then I would like to take this opportunity to introduce to you
それではこの機会にぜひご紹介したいと思います
We now have the development of a new generation of earthquake science
私たちは今、新世代の地震科学を開発しています。
and why do we need this thing
そしてなぜこれが必要なのでしょうか
Of course, there are still many challenges in it.
もちろん、そこにはまだ多くの課題があります。
but i think it's the future
でもそれは未来だと思う
Towards that job, of course I am the main leader
その仕事に対しては、もちろん私がメインリーダーです
But it takes a lot of teams to actually execute
しかし、実際に実行するには多くのチームが必要です
Because it actually has a lot of technology in it
実際にたくさんのテクノロジーが組み込まれているので、
Not just data analysis Data analysis is
データ分析だけではない データ分析は
Now let's enjoy data analysis
さあ、データ分析を楽しみましょう
But in the first two years it was actually a lot of labor work
しかし、最初の 2 年間は実際には大変な労働でした
researchers of technologies that matter to our planet
私たちの地球にとって重要なテクノロジーの研究者
they are very important roles
彼らはとても重要な役割です
Dr. Lin Qingren Dr. Gu Jinshang
リン・チンレン博士 グ・ジンシャン博士
And researcher Huang Xinhua
研究者の黄新華氏と
This is a very elite key figure in the whole team
これはチーム全体の非常にエリートの重要人物です
Then it's me and Germany
それなら私とドイツです
Especially Sabastian and Philip
特にサバスティアンとフィリップ
their instruments in europe
ヨーロッパでの彼らの楽器
They first lent us the equipment
最初に機材を貸していただきました
Let's understand what characterizes the whole instrument
楽器全体の特徴を理解しましょう
So I am very happy to tell you today
だから今日は皆さんにお伝えできてとても嬉しいです
Launch the Seismic Light Generation
地震光発電を開始する
Then I believe that those who are doing
そうすれば、やっている人たちは、
It should be a little bit about earthquakes
地震についても少し触れておこう
So what I'm talking about may be more popular than general science.
したがって、私が話していることは、一般的な科学よりも人気があるかもしれません。
slightly higher
やや高いです
a little deeper
もう少し深く
but i think
しかし、私は思います
This is a knowledge experiment at the hospital of traditional Chinese medicine
これは中医院での知識実験です
and the audience may be more able to
そして聴衆はもっとできるかもしれない
what you want to contact
連絡したいこと
So I will talk a little bit
それで少し話します
General science is a little deeper
一般科学はもう少し深い
Well, of course earthquake observation I just mentioned
まあ、もちろん、さっき言った地震観測
I am honored to be in
参加できて光栄です
When I graduated from my Ph.D.
私が博士課程を卒業したとき、
The result is that the entire earthquake becomes broadband
その結果、地震全体がブロードバンド化される
The observation is that I go from 1Hz to
観察によると、1Hzから
1Hz should mean from 0.01 seconds
1Hz は 0.01 秒からを意味します
I can write it all down to 100Hz
100Hzまですべて書き込むことができます
So this is what we call a broadband seismic network.
これが広帯域地震観測網と呼ばれるものです。
In fact, in the hospital of traditional Chinese medicine
実は中医院では
Dr. Liang Wenzhong We started to promote
梁文中博士 私たちは宣伝を始めました
的 Broadband Array in Seismology
地震学におけるブロードバンドアレイ
This is BATS
こちらはバッツです
At that time, I was in the Earth Institute of the Hospital of Traditional Chinese Medicine
当時、私は中医院地球研究所にいました。
He has been in seismology in Taiwan
彼は台湾で地震学を研究していた
play a very important role
非常に重要な役割を果たします
That is, whenever an earthquake occurs
つまり、地震が起こるたびに、
Whether it's the shock of all the boots
ブーツ全体の衝撃かどうか
or any earthquake in the world
あるいは世界中のどんな地震でも
happened we can all remember
私たち全員が覚えていることが起こった
Well, of course it has something to do with the work of the weather bureau.
もちろん気象局の仕事と関係があります。
Of course it's very close
もちろんとても近いです
From the Odds Bureau, it is of course more biased towards large-scale earthquakes
オッズ局からは、もちろん大規模地震に偏っています。
Scale 4 Scale 5 It's gonna start doing some of these enouncements of earthquakes
スケール 4 スケール 5 地震の予告が始まります
Its location may not be as precise as ours
その位置は私たちの位置ほど正確ではない可能性があります
But it needs to be within the fastest time
ただし、最速の時間以内である必要があります
Tell everyone where the earthquake is and how big it is
地震がどこでどれくらいの大きさかをみんなに伝えてください
But with the role of BETS of the Central Plains Earth Institute
しかし、セントラルプレーンズ地球研究所のBETSの役割により
It's just that I am very accurate for small earthquakes.
ただ、小さな地震に関しては非常に正確です。
Then my scale also has a certain scale relationship
そうすると、私のスケールにも一定のスケール関係があります
Only then can I have a series of high-quality data for earthquake research
そうして初めて、地震研究のための一連の高品質なデータを得ることができるのです。
Then this high-quality data is not just a study of Taiwan
この質の高いデータは単なる台湾の研究ではありません
is the world's earthquake science
は世界の地震科学です
Of course I think it's the same in every field of science.
もちろん、それはどの科学分野でも同じだと思います。
That is, earthquake science is a very international research science.
つまり、地震科学は非常に国際的な研究科学なのです。
Because of the large-scale earthquake, the so-called large-scale is scale 7 scale 8
大規模な地震のため、いわゆる大規模とは規模7、規模8です。
Of course we don't want it to happen often
もちろん、それが頻繁に起こることは望ましくありません
but as soon as it happened
しかし、それが起こるとすぐに
The world wants to be able to share this material and understand its uniqueness
世界はこの素材を共有し、その独自性を理解できるようにしたいと考えています
In particular, seismology is a very science of earthquake observation
特に、地震学はまさに地震観測の科学です。
It must have earthquake observation and disaster status
地震観測や災害状況がわかること
The more refined we are
洗練されれば洗練されるほど
theories of our science
私たちの科学の理論
Then make the basis of disaster prevention
そして防災の基礎を作る
So here at the Zhongyingyuan
ここ中営園です
In fact, it has always played a very important role
実際、それは常に非常に重要な役割を果たしてきました
This is from Teacher Liang Wenzhong
梁文中先生からです
We are on the official website of the Earth Institute of the Zhongying Institute
私たちは中営研究所地球研究所の公式ウェブサイトにいます
Show it directly and GPS ground deformation
直接見せてGPS地盤変形
That is, except for the situation that happened during the earthquake
つまり、地震の際に起こった状況を除いて、
I still need to know
まだ知る必要がある
Entire plate collides with Taiwan
プレート全体が台湾に衝突
how is it
どうですか
how energy is accumulated
エネルギーはどのように蓄積されるのか
how much it accumulated
どれくらい貯まったか
how fast it accumulates
どのくらいの速さで蓄積するのか
that of course is back to us
それはもちろん私たちに返ってきます
It was later shown with the so-called seismic hazard
それは後にいわゆる地震の危険性とともに示されました
such a job
そんな仕事
Then this is actually for Backbone
これは実際にはBackbone用です
Just one he must be stable
ただ一つ、彼は安定していなければならない
and he can't disconnect
そして彼は接続を切ることができない
And permanently maintain the highest quality signal
最高品質の信号を永続的に維持します
Then this quality control
それからこの品質管理
Of course the most important thing
もちろん一番大切なことは
that besides this
これ以外に
Many developments in the past twenty or thirty years
過去 20 年または 30 年の間に多くの発展があった
Although I just talked about the generation of light
先ほど光の生成についてお話しましたが、
It's not that we were twenty or thirty years ago
20年も30年も前のことじゃない
didn't do anything
何もしませんでした
but twenty or thirty years ago
でも20年か30年前
we have started to develop
私たちは開発を始めました
the entire earthquake signal
地震信号全体
Hope to prevent disasters from earthquakes
地震による災害を防ぎたい
Just mentioned by the vice president
先ほど副社長がおっしゃった
A very important role in our earthquake science is
私たちの地震科学における非常に重要な役割は、
give back to society
社会に還元する
when an earthquake occurs
地震が起きたとき
how the hell do we get
一体どうやって手に入れるのですか
what is the fastest message
最速のメッセージは何ですか
So this is a solemn admission
これは厳粛な告白です
the same is within us
同じことが私たちの中にもあります
Dr. Li Xianzhong received
李賢中博士が受賞
is our signal
私たちの信号です
the signal just said
信号が今言った
In fact I am every second
実際、私は毎秒
Actually every 0.01 seconds
実際には0.01秒ごと
The signal keeps coming in
信号が入り続けている
So let's build
それでは、構築しましょう
Database of Seismic Waves of All Taiwan
台湾全土の地震波データベース
Then as long as the earthquake comes every two seconds
それから、2秒ごとに地震が起こる限り
In fact, whether there is an earthquake or not
実際、地震があろうがなかろうが、
Every two seconds I react by myself
2秒ごとに自分で反応する
Going to explain my current vibration
私の現在の波動を説明します
Is it an earthquake
地震ですか
Therefore, we can quickly
したがって、すぐに
two seconds or even ten seconds
2秒、あるいは10秒でも
we can book the earthquake
地震を予約できます
size
規模大小
and its location
とその場所
that this is now
これが今だということ
There are many collaborations with the weather track list
ウェザートラックリストとのコラボレーションも多数
or everyone here
またはここにいるみんな
may work for us
私たちに役立つかもしれない
some familiar words
いくつかのおなじみの言葉
That's when we have an earthquake every time
毎回地震が起こるのはそのときです
We will directly poss up
直接お届けいたします
Many friends also directly
多くの友人も直接
just look online
ただオンラインで見てください
I see a lot of friends on Facebook
Facebookでたくさんの友達に会います
So directly put this network
したがって、このネットワークを直接配置します
As far as the post is concerned, where is the earthquake?
投稿に関する限り、地震はどこにありますか?
For example, this is the Hualien earthquake on February 6, 2018
例えば、これは2018年2月6日の花蓮地震です。
At this moment, of course we can put
この時点では、もちろん、
size, depth
サイズ、深さ
Solve for its positive element mechanism
ポジティブ要素のメカニズムを解決する
All solved and its maximum position
すべて解決された状態とその最大位置
That's totally intelligent
それは完全に知的ですね
It is completely Online
完全にオンラインです
Then Real Time directly and automatically
その後、リアルタイムで直接かつ自動的に
do the program work
プログラムの仕事をする
Then this is one of the very important contributions
これは非常に重要な貢献の 1 つです
It is just mentioned in the past 10 years
ここ10年くらいで言われただけだよ
Taiwan Earthquake Science Center
台湾地震科学センター
important work done
重要な仕事が終わった
outside of scientific research
科学研究以外のところで
How to really feedback the information of the whole Society
社会全体の情報をいかに真にフィードバックするか
Well, this is of course another important task.
まあ、これももちろん重要な仕事です。
is also in
も入っています
It will be seen in the official website of the Earth Institute
地球研究所の公式ウェブサイトで見ることができます
every time an earthquake occurs
地震が起こるたびに
There will be more than 600 steps in Taiwan
台湾には600段以上の階段があります
We get Real Time's Share Map anytime
リアルタイムのシェアマップをいつでも入手できます
the vibration chart
振動チャート
In fact, earthquake disaster prevention is very important
実は地震防災はとても大切です
say it's a beauty earthquake
それは美しい地震だと言う
Maybe everyone is in the middle of the night and it's New Year's Eve
たぶんみんな真夜中で大晦日だよ
so no one knows what's going on
だから何が起こっているのか誰も分からない
But if you come directly to this page
ただし、このページに直接アクセスした場合は、
You can see that I am in Kaohsiung Tainan
私は台南の高雄にいることが分かります
Vibrations with a magnitude of 7 or higher are generated near here
この付近でマグニチュード7以上の振動が発生しています
That's because our earthquake blood is researching
それは私たちの地震の血が研究しているからです
We know this is bound to produce disaster
これが必ず大惨事を引き起こすことを私たちは知っています
At the beginning, it was also NCDR who directly contacted and said
当初、直接連絡を取ってこう言ったのもNCDRでした。
kink
よじれる
it will surely produce disaster
それは必ず災いをもたらすだろう
Then make direct contact with other units of the fire department
その後、消防署の他の部隊と直接連絡を取ります。
Then this part is also the shake map of real time every five seconds
するとこの部分も5秒ごとのリアルタイムのシェイクマップになります
That's because our Central Plains Institute is currently
それは、私たちのセントラルプレーンズ研究所が現在、
There are many things that need to be strengthened in terms of law and order
法と秩序の面で強化すべきことがたくさんある
So we are currently offline
したがって、現在オフラインです
Because of the maintenance of the security firewall
セキュリティファイアウォールのメンテナンスのため
That's another challenge
それはまた別の挑戦です
That is, I want to open data
つまりデータをオープンにしたい
But I also need a very good firewall
しかし、非常に優れたファイアウォールも必要です
it's a bit of a dilemma
それは少しジレンマです
but we want to find the balance
でも私たちはバランスを見つけたいのです
Then this is all open to all people can use
そうすれば、これはすべての人が使用できるようになります
of course i now
もちろん私は今
I know Teacher Liang just met him
リャン先生が彼に会ったばかりだと知っています
Said he would come too
彼も来ると言った
we now hope
私たちは今願っています
I can play this real time intensity directly to
このリアルタイムの激しさを直接再生できます
above the person's position
その人の立場より上
If you put it in the corner where you are
あなたがいる隅っこに置いたら
That's what we want to develop now
それが私たちが今開発したいことです
work related to communication
コミュニケーションに関わる仕事
Then this is actually
それから、これは実は
What we have done over the years
私たちが長年にわたってやってきたこと
Of course, these jobs have already played a certain role.
もちろん、これらの仕事はすでに一定の役割を果たしています。
Especially since everyone has become familiar with
特に誰もが慣れ親しんだものになってからは、
what early warning message
早期警告メッセージは何ですか
some people will mention
言及する人もいるでしょう
is he borderline
彼は境界線にいるのか
why didn't he receive
なぜ彼は受け取らなかったのか
why did he receive blah blah blah
なぜ彼はなんとか受け取ったのですか
Of course if you want to be accurate
もちろん正確に知りたければ
It must be very high resolution
非常に解像度が高いはずです
Because everyone has heard that I am in Shichenglou
私が石城楼にいるということは誰もが聞いているからです
You said the vibration level is 2
振動レベルは2だと言いましたね
I can't, I'm shaking too much
できない、震えすぎている
OK because Shicheng Tower has different
石城塔は違うからOK
different shake sizes
さまざまなシェイクサイズ
There is someone in the Taipei Basin who has been shaking for a long time
台北盆地に長い間揺れ続けている人がいる
Some people shake it better on the side of the mountain
山の側でよく振る人もいる
not so long
そう長くはありません
But with the current earthquake stations in Taiwan
しかし、台湾の現在の地震観測所では
Probably more than 10 kilometers as a resolution
おそらく解像度としては10キロメートル以上
Well, that's still important in this part.
まあ、それはこの部分でも重要です。
We must say that this most basic backbone
この最も基本的なバックボーンは、
is to keep all signals stable
すべての信号を安定に保つことです
important key observation network
重要な重要な観測ネットワーク
then it can instantly locate the scale mechanism
そうすれば、スケール機構を即座に見つけることができます
That probably means we have meteorological laws when we go to Taiwan.
それはおそらく、台湾に行くときは気象法があるということです。
basically we can't announce the location of the earthquake
基本的に地震の発生場所は発表できません
We want the weather bureau to announce
気象庁に発表してほしい
then what we do is meteorology
では私たちがやっているのは気象学です
But we are after this real time Maping
しかし、私たちはこのリアルタイム マッピングを目指しています
There is some interaction with the Meteorological Bureau
気象庁とのやりとりもある
So but sometimes you'll see that the scale is a little bit different
でも時々、スケールが少し違うことに気づくでしょう
the location is a bit different
場所は少し違います
That is we probably every earthquake is like last time
それはおそらくどの地震も前回と同じだろう
Ikegami Earthquake
池上地震
September's Ikegami Earthquake
9月の池上地震
a week later
一週間後
We'll have a joint seminar with the Bureau of Meteorology
気象庁との共催セミナーを開催します
Discuss all communication and
すべてのコミュニケーションについて話し合い、
Understanding and analyzing data, etc.
データの理解・分析等
Well, that's actually going to really see some
まあ、それは実際にいくつかを見ることになるでしょう
More precise slices
より正確なスライス
For example, the structure of the Taipei Flat just mentioned
例えば、先ほどの台北フラットの構造は、
you are next to the fault
あなたは間違いの隣にいます
on the hanging wall of the fault you are on the foot wall of the fault
断層の垂れ下がった壁の上で、あなたは断層の麓の壁の上にいる
etc
等
You need a lot of more detailed data analysis
より詳細なデータ分析が必要になる
that in the past few years
それはここ数年で
In fact, it is just a Geofone Array
実際には、それは単なる Geofone アレイです
That is, you will, we will go out into the field to set up a few side stations
つまり、あなたもそうでしょう、私たちはフィールドに出て、いくつかのサイドステーションを設置します
Which station may be how to go is about a kilometer away
どの駅へどう行けばよいか約1キロメートル離れています
but you need it to have battery impact
ただし、バッテリーに影響を与えるために必要です
It may be operable for about a month, three months
1ヶ月、3ヶ月くらいは使えるかもしれない
but you will do it with your needs
しかし、あなたはあなたのニーズに合わせてそれを行うでしょう
Well, this actually did a lot
まあ、これは実際に多くのことを行いました
Especially now that there was a geothermal seminar yesterday
特に昨日は地熱セミナーがあったので
You mentioned a lot of this kind of Geofone
この種の Geofone についてたくさん言及しましたね
To probe the entire structure in high resolution
高解像度で構造全体を調査するには
OK, but while this high-resolution detection
OK、ただし、この高解像度の検出は
There's something new, and it's called fiber optics.
新しいものがあって、それは光ファイバーと呼ばれるものです。
In fact, everyone is using this optical fiber now.
実は今、誰もがこの光ファイバーを使っています。
It is Chunghwa Telecom, you will see 5G optical fiber
中華電信です、5G光ファイバーが見えます
you have a cable
ケーブルをお持ちですか
The current practice is to say
現在の慣行は次のとおりです
how do i bury us in the ground
どうやって私たちを土の中に埋めるの？
Chunghwa Telecom these cables
中華電信のケーブル
It becomes the observation of the earthquake chair
地震椅子の観測になります
Then its main job is to say
その場合、その主な仕事は次のとおりです。
I'm next to all the fibers
私はすべての繊維の隣にいる
Adding a DARS here is a
ここに DARS を追加すると、
that is
あれは
Distributed Acoustic Sensing
分散型音響センシング
it actually shoots a laser beam out
実際にレーザー光線を発射します
Then if you talk about disturbance
じゃあ騒動について言えば
When the laser beam returns
レーザー光が戻ってくると
you will have a phase change
位相変化が起こるでしょう
Phase change from
位相からの変化
I can figure it out and say
私はそれを理解して言うことができます
How much does it disturb
どれくらい邪魔しますか
how much disturbance
どれくらいの妨害か
Of course I can decide
もちろん決められるよ
Where did this disturbance come from?
この騒動はどこから来たのでしょうか？
the fiber optic
光ファイバー
Monitoring Of course it's not just
モニタリング もちろんそれだけではありません
do earthquake
地震をする
car waves weather water
車の波天気水
all can
すべてできる
Well, I'm just more focused today.
まあ、今日はもっと集中してます。
to mention its relationship to earthquakes
地震との関係について言及する
That's my current job
それが私の現在の仕事です
already like i last week
すでに先週のように
Three months in Caltic in the United States
アメリカのカルティックで3ヶ月
work i know has done froding
私が知っている仕事はフロッディングを行った
It's now
雪が降る
America is now flooding
アメリカは今洪水になっている
flooded quite seriously
かなり深刻な浸水
It's about this aspect of Froding
それはフローディングのこの側面についてです
natural test is
自然なテストは
is allowed
許可されています
of course this part
もちろんこの部分も
We still have many challenges
私たちにはまだ多くの課題があります
I'm buried in the ground
私は地面に埋もれています
Then all disturbances will be sent
そうすればすべての妨害が送信されます
So how do I tell if it's a signal
では、それが信号かどうかをどうやって判断すればよいのでしょうか
still an earthquake
まだ地震
That requires a lot of data analysis of big data
それにはビッグデータの大量のデータ分析が必要です
so i will say
だから私は言います
I am honored that in my senior years
シニアの年にこうしていただけて光栄です
Senior this experience when
先輩がこの経験をしたとき
to another generation
別の世代へ
Of course, this is even more interdisciplinary.
もちろん、これはさらに学際的なものです。
it's not earthquake blood
それは地震の血ではありません
It also includes the training of the AI
AIのトレーニングも含まれます
Training materials for Machine Learning
Machine Learning的訓練資料
Because its data is a few terabytes a day
そのデータは1日あたり数テラバイトであるため、
how about the whole data
データ全体はどうですか
make it fast and accurate
速くて正確にする
that's another challenge
それはまた別の挑戦だ
that job of course
もちろんその仕事
Just mentioned I've been thinking about saying
さっき言いました、言おうと思ってたんです
Is it possible to do this
これは可能ですか
Advancing our earthquake science
地震科学の進歩
to what extent
どの程度まで
Actually, I've been thinking about it
実はずっと考えてたんです
That is, I can increase the resolution to a higher
つまり、解像度をさらに高くすることができます
So how can I parse
では、どうやって解析すればよいのでしょうか
Problems in Earthquake Physics
地震物理学の問題
to what extent
どの程度まで
this is my thinking
これが私の考えです
But in terms of structure, it is absolutely possible to have higher-resolution structural analysis
しかし、構造に関しては、より高解像度の構造解析を行うことは絶対に可能です。
Can it improve the accuracy of our earthquake early warning?
緊急地震速報の精度は向上するでしょうか？
Accuracy of Earthquakes
地震動的準確度
For example, if you have a shock level of 2 and a shock level of 3
たとえば、ショック レベル 2 とショック レベル 3 がある場合、
Can I get the correct data more accurately?
正しいデータをより正確に取得できますか?
That's not to mention looking at energy
エネルギーに注目することは言うまでもありません
Because I just saw colleagues from Taipower come over
Taipower の同僚が来たところを見たからです
or some of the other ex-friends
または他の元友人の何人か
Now we are talking about carbon dioxide storage in Taiwan
今、私たちは台湾の二酸化炭素貯留について話しています。
Green energy and so on
グリーンエネルギーなど
So if I pump carbon dioxide into the ground today
だから今日、二酸化炭素を地面に汲み上げたら
how carbon dioxide travels
二酸化炭素はどのように移動するのか
We can also map it out
計画を立てることもできます
because I can put all the signals
すべての信号を入れることができるから
All perturbations down to a few micro and even down to a Nano
数マイクロ、さらにはナノに至るまでのすべての摂動
can detect it
それを検出できる
Everyone, see where my Fiber is placed
みんな、私のファイバーがどこに置かれているか見てください
That's now geothermal carbon sequestration
それが地熱炭素隔離です
Or if you have questions about geothermal energy
地熱エネルギーについて質問がある場合は、
geothermal exploration
地熱探看
For example in Finland
例えばフィンランドでは
Or another earthquake in the Netherlands because of geothermal carbon deposits
それとも地熱炭素堆積物が原因でオランダでまた地震が起きるのか
So shut down the whole factory
だから工場全部止めろよ
Is there a way for us to come up with some solutions for this part?
この部分について何か解決策を考え出すことはできないでしょうか？
So it can be applied in a wide range of
なので幅広い用途に応用できます
Then I just talk about it today as the beginning of an era of light
それから今日は光の時代の始まりとしてそれについて話します
I must say the whole thing I'm going to share today
今日共有する内容をすべて言わなければなりません
In fact, the future may be even more exciting
実際、未来はさらにエキサイティングになるかもしれません
Today is just a bit of a kick off feeling
今日はちょっとしたキックオフ気分です
Well, the application of this is of course
まあ、これを応用するのは当然ですが、
why so accurate
なぜそんなに正確なのか
we generally speaking
私たちは一般的に言えば
Of course when the earthquake comes
もちろん地震が来たら
you want to shake
揺れたいですか
know how much i shake
私がどれだけ震えているか知っていますか
But our real challenge is to say
しかし、私たちの本当の課題はこう言うことです
the beginning of the earthquake
地震一開始
when the first person starts shaking
最初の人が震え始めたとき
Do you know if it will be a scale seven or a scale eight
スケール 7 かスケール 8 になるか知っていますか?
or do you think it's only scale five
それともスケール5だけだと思いますか？
Yes, we are usually when the earthquake hits
はい、地震が起こるときはいつも私たちがいます
whether you were warned
警告されたかどうか
You must feel it first
まずはそれを感じなければなりません
How big is my earthquake?
私の地震はどれくらいの大きさですか?
when you really get nervous
本当に緊張したとき
it just stopped
それはちょうど止まった
but can we do it
でも、できるでしょうか
Do we have scientifically
科学的にはありますか
This ability even physically understands
身体でもわかるこの能力
Is there a way to know the beginning of an earthquake?
地震の始まりを知る方法はありますか?
How big will it become? Is it possible?
どのくらい大きくなるのですか?可能ですか?
Well, of course, this raises a lot of scientific issues.
もちろん、これには多くの科学的疑問が生じます。
But in general industry
しかし、一般的な業界では
The industry began to make a lot of contact with us
業界は私たちと多くのコンタクトを取り始めました
He will tell me, Mr. Mao, I am not doing earthquake prediction.
彼は私に、毛沢東さん、私は地震予知をしているわけではない、と言うでしょう。
but can you tell me how long this earthquake will shake
でもこの地震はどれくらい揺れるか教えてもらえますか
Or can I make my machine
それとも自分でマシンを作ってもいいですか
Such as the semiconductor process
半導体プロセスなど
I know when my machine shakes to 20G
マシンが 20G まで揺れるときはわかります
it may contaminate can i let it be mentioned
汚染されている可能性がありますので、言及してもいいでしょうか
It takes 3 seconds when I mention it takes 2 seconds
2秒かかると言ったら3秒かかる
can i do it
やってもいいですか
So with this kind of dialogue, I actually feel that
このような対話をしていると、私は実際に次のように感じます。
very important conversation let me think
とても重要な会話を考えさせてください
what can i do
私に何ができる
Then this part of the information becomes very important
この部分の情報は非常に重要になります
For example, when this signal comes in
たとえば、この信号が入ったとき
when this signal comes in
この信号が入ってくると
I just mentioned my little signal from the beginning
最初から私の小さな信号について触れました
you haven't you probably haven't felt yet
あなたはまだ感じていないかもしれません
But suppose I
しかし、私が
has a very sharp fiber optic
非常に鋭利な光ファイバーを備えています
even very close side stand
非常に近いサイドスタンドでも
I can tell it's already a signal
もう信号だとわかるよ
Then I know that from this signal
この信号からそれがわかります
can know this signal
信号を知ることができる
It arrives at the maximum acceleration value
最大加速値に到達
Does it have a certain regression relationship?
一定の回帰関係があるのでしょうか？
How many seconds will it take me to be sure?
確認するまでに何秒かかりますか?
Will this earthquake cause disaster?
この地震は災害を引き起こすでしょうか？
I may have no way of knowing where the earthquake is right away
どこで地震が起きたかすぐには分からないかもしれない
Because earthquake location takes time
地震の位置特定に時間がかかるため
You have to have at least three stations to receive
受信するには少なくとも 3 つのステーションが必要です
that's earthquake scale
それは地震規模です
You may not be so accurate right away.
すぐには正確に判断できないかもしれません。
But I know when I shake to a certain degree
でもある程度揺れるとわかるんです
For example, our human feelings
たとえば、私たち人間の感情
I think everyone in Taiwan must have felt an earthquake
台湾の人はみんな地震を感じたと思います
When you shake for more than 10 seconds
10秒以上振ると
you will start to get nervous
あなたは緊張し始めるでしょう
Do you think that this earthquake will
この地震は起こると思いますか?
I should protect myself
自分を守らなければなりません
Is there even a disaster
災害でもあるのか
Then our seismology
それでは私たちの地震学は
about 3 seconds
約3秒
That is what we tell us from our empirical data
それが私たちの経験的データから言えることです
3 seconds before the earthquake signal comes in
地震信号が入る3秒前
It can tell us it's about to turn into a catastrophic earthquake
それは、壊滅的な地震に変わりつつあることを私たちに知らせることができます
or not a catastrophic earthquake
壊滅的な地震ではないのか
That is to say, after it comes up in 3 seconds,
つまり、3秒以内に起動した後、
it may go down
下がるかもしれない
After 3 seconds it keeps going
3秒後も動き続ける
If you continue walking after 3 seconds
3秒後に歩き続けると
it can produce disaster
それは災害を引き起こす可能性があります
Although I don't know if it's scale 7 or scale 8
スケール7なのかスケール8なのかは分かりませんが
but it will have disasters
しかし、それには災害が起こるだろう
So I gave a warning
それで私は警告を出しました
These are some related concepts of earthquake early warning
これらは緊急地震速報に関連する概念です。
Of course, in terms of decision-making
もちろん意思決定に関しても
It's whether I can be in that moment
その瞬間にいられるかどうかだ
just make a decision
ただ決断を下すだけ
Of course, this decision must be an intelligent one.
もちろん、この決定は賢明なものでなければなりません。
So this is a high-resolution signal
これは高解像度信号です
its important precision
重要な精度
That's why I was referring to the fiber optic
私が光ファイバーについて言及したのはそのためです
Can we make this more precise
これをもっと正確にできないか
Because we don't want to have Force Alarm either
強制アラームも使いたくないので
In general industry
一般産業では
Force Alarm it also loses a lot
強制アラームでもかなりの損失が発生します
so they have to say
だから彼らは言わなければならない
I need to know my Early Warning
早期警告を知りたい
But I'm not a Force Alarm
でも私はフォースアラームではない
Otherwise, my Impact would be huge
そうでなければ、私の影響は非常に大きくなるでしょう
So that's the whole challenge in this place
それがこの場所でのすべての挑戦です
Of course, this is an industrial application
もちろん産業用途です
It's about earthquake science.
地震科学についてです。
Great connection with the social body of the whole society
社会全体の社会体との大きなつながり
Of course it also mentioned Taiwan
もちろん台湾についても触れています
I think the news is familiar
そのニュースはよく知られていると思います
Taiwan's semiconductor
台湾の半導体
is important to us
私たちにとって重要です
very important economic value
非常に重要な経済的価値
Then Taiwan is a place with multiple arrays
それから台湾は複数のアレイがある場所です
then many people will want to say
そうすれば多くの人が言いたくなるだろう
Then I may have a lot of losses
そうしたら大損するかもしれない
Then I also thought
それから私も思いました
This is the situation facing Taiwan
これが台湾の現状だ
So what angle does our science use?
それでは、私たちの科学はどのような角度から活用しているのでしょうか？
can be impacted in this area when
この領域は次の場合に影響を受ける可能性があります。
keep us
私たちを維持
won't be affected too much
あまり影響されないだろう
At the same time, it has also become a business opportunity for us
同時にそれは私たちにとってビジネスチャンスでもあります
It is now that the whole world is developing
今は全世界が発展している時代です
In 2010, of course, Japan is doing a lot
2010年、もちろん日本は多くのことを行っています
California is doing it too
カリフォルニアもやってるよ
Italy and other countries are doing
イタリアや他の国はやっている
But we have the most earthquake signals
しかし、私たちは最も多くの地震信号を持っています
that's because you want to train
それはトレーニングしたいからです
You need a lot of data
大量のデータが必要です
Then Taiwan is a large amount of information
それから台湾は情報量が多いです
important database
重要なデータベース
That's another
それは別です
If the earthquake is far away from me
地震が遠くにあるなら
That Early Warning is useless
早期警戒は役に立たない
That is to say, five or six years ago
つまり5～6年前
But mainland China is developing a lot Early Warning
しかし、中国本土は大きく発展しています 早期警告
Then the news mentioned that
そしたらニュースでこう言われました
Earthquake warnings in Taiwan are poor
台湾の地震警報は弱い
Only three seconds, five seconds
たった3秒、5秒
Look at the earthquake in Sichuan in Japan
日本の四川省の地震を見てみよう
It can warn earthquakes for 20 to 30 seconds
20～30秒間地震を警告します
In fact, there is a concept to know
実は知っておくべき概念があります
Twenty seconds, thirty seconds means the earthquake is very, very far away from you
20秒、30秒は、地震があなたから非常に遠いことを意味します
Giving you an Early Warning is actually useless
早期警告を与えることは実際には役に立たない
Because I can't say it's useless
無駄とは言えないから
It should mean that it does not actually cause disasters
それは実際に災害を引き起こさないことを意味するはずです
so sometimes we talk
だから時々話します
Early Warning sometimes becomes Entertainment
早期警戒は時にエンターテイメントになる
That's the earthquake warning
それは地震警報です
Huh? Did you get it?
え？分かりましたか？
Huh? Why didn't I get it? Why didn't you get it?
え? なんでわかってないの? なんでわかってないの?
In fact the whole real purpose is to reduce the shock
実際、本当の目的はショックを軽減することです
But sometimes there's this aspect
でもたまにこういう側面もあるよ
become everyone comparing me
私を比較するみんなになる
under what conditions
どのような条件下で
Of course, this is something we have discussed a lot with the Qiathlon Bureau and the NCD.
もちろん、これは私たちがQiathlon BureauおよびNCDと何度も話し合ったものです。
That is, we must all test
つまり、私たちは皆テストしなければなりません
Everyone can receive this message accurately
誰もがこのメッセージを正確に受け取ることができます
Okay back to the science question
さて、科学の質問に戻ります
There are many important scientific challenges
重要な科学的課題が数多くあります
that is
あれは
i hope what we do
私たちがやることを願っています
except for the folk
庶民を除いて
Beyond contributions that are important to our country
我が国にとって重要な貢献以外にも
Taiwan's role in earthquake science
地震科学における台湾の役割
What kind of leadership can there be in the world
世界にはどのようなリーダーシップがあり得るのか
scientific value
科学的価値
that just mentioned
それは今言った
Everyone is most concerned about earthquake prediction
誰もが最も関心があるのは地震予知です
as long as i say i am a seismologist
私が地震学者であると言う限り
Including customs clearance to the United States
米国への通関を含む
As long as I say I'm a Sesemologist
私がセセモロストであると言う限り、
He immediately asked me if I could do earthquake prediction
彼はすぐに私に地震予知ができるかどうか尋ねました
Earthquake prediction is a matter of concern to everyone.
地震予知は誰もが関心を持つ事柄です。
Is it possible that he
もしかして彼は
I just mentioned the earthquake
先ほど地震のことを言いました
he was at the beginning
彼は最初にいた
Do you know how big he has become?
彼がどれくらい大きくなったか知っていますか？
How exactly did the earthquake start?
地震は正確にどのように始まったのでしょうか?
how did he end
彼はどうやって終わったのか
In fact, there is still no answer
実はまだ答えは出ていない
then i keep saying
それから私は言い続けます
If you don't know how an earthquake starts
地震がどうやって起きるか分からないなら
don't know how he ended
彼がどう終わったかわからない
You can't do earthquake prediction at all
地震予知なんて全然できないよ
Earthquake predictions just stay in statistics
地震予知は統計にとどまる
statistics it has a certain value
統計には特定の値があります
the industry I just mentioned
さっき言った業界
they want to know
彼らは知りたいのです
earthquake forecasting
地震的 forecasting
how is the estimate
見積もりはどうですか
Then we have a certain theory
それから、ある理論があります
can do this work
この仕事ができる
But earthquake prediction works
でも地震予知は当たる
He still has many challenges
彼にはまだ多くの課題がある
I even often say
私もよく言います
If the earthquake prediction is successful
地震予知が当たったら
Earthquakes will still come
地震はまだ来るだろう
Not that you predict earthquakes
地震を予知するわけではない
Earthquakes don't come, right?
地震は来ないですよね？
so you really do work
だからあなたは本当に仕事をしているのね
In fact, earthquake disaster prevention
実は地震防災
and earthquake warning
そして地震警報
even
平
If Earthquake Prediction Fails
地震予知が外れた場合
the disaster he caused
彼が引き起こした災害
Possibly worse than a real earthquake disaster
実際の地震災害よりも深刻になる可能性がある
Right, you can think about it
そう、考えてもいいよ
If I talk about a
について話したら
Taiwan may be within a week
台湾は1週間以内かもしれない
A scale period of earthquakes
マグニチュード周期地震
Stocks may plummet
株価暴落の可能性
everyone wants to go abroad
誰もが海外に行きたいと思っています
or where are you going
それともどこへ行くのですか
last time there was a tsunami
前回津波があったとき
The first tsunami alarm
最初の津波警報
As a result, there was a traffic jam on the highway.
その結果、高速道路で渋滞が発生した。
that this is actually
これが実際にあるということ
When we're working on this
これに取り組んでいるとき
how are we getting ready
準備はどうですか
Then I often used to talk to students
それから私はよく生徒たちと話していました
my dream but my dream i don't think i can make it
私の夢だけど私の夢は達成できないと思う
That's me, if the earthquake prediction is successful
地震予知が当たったら、それが私です
Then make it a hundred times the energy into a real energy that can be used
そしてその100倍のエネルギーを実際に使えるエネルギーに変える
I think earthquake prediction is feasible
地震予知は可能だと思う
or worth doing
あるいはやる価値がある
Otherwise the work we do
それ以外の場合は、私たちの仕事
Earthquake early warning and earthquake disaster prevention
緊急地震速報と地震防災
How do we proceed with earthquake early warning and earthquake disaster prevention?
緊急地震速報、地震防災をどう進めるか。
For example, how do I put Taiwan but the whole world is the same
たとえば、台湾はどう言えばいいのですが、世界は同じです。
The location of these fault zones that may produce earthquakes in Taiwan
台湾で地震を引き起こす可能性のある断層帯の位置
not very clear
あまり明確ではない
This is what we do with geologists
これが地質学者と私たちがやっていることです
However, the Geological Survey Institute, the Meteorological Bureau, and many related units
ただし、地質調査所、気象庁、その他多くの関係機関は、
how do i know where the fault is
どこに障害があるのか​​をどうやって知ることができますか
When will this fault move?
この断層はいつ動くのでしょうか？
how much does it move
どれくらい動きますか
If it moves, what about the mayor of Taipei?
もし動いたら、台北市長はどうなるでしょうか？
what will happen
何が起こるか
what will happen to my family
私の家族はどうなりますか
the location of a place how it will be
場所の場所、それはどうなるか
That's what we're talking about now
それが今私たちが話していることです
National Disaster Prevention Science and Technology Center
国立防災科学技術センター
Or something that the Ministry of the Interior Interdepartmental Council is doing
あるいは内務省の省庁間委員会がやっている事か
It is a drill for a large-scale earthquake every September
毎年9月に大規模地震を想定した訓練です
But this part is not precise enough
しかし、この部分は十分に正確ではありません
That's how I know about earthquake fault systems
私はそうやって地震断層システムについて知っています
For example, the Chishang earthquake on September 18
例えば、9月18日の池上地震。
It moves both faults
両方の断層を動かす
Central Sanpai fault to the west
西側の中央サンパイ断層
Chishang Fault to the east
東に池上断層
both moved
両方とも移動しました
The 1906 Meishan Earthquake
1906 年の眉山地震
It actually you see an east-west Meishan fault
実際には東西の眉山断層が見えます
But in fact its real motion structure
しかし実際には、その実際の運動構造は
is the movement structure underneath
その下の運動構造です
Then the reverse fault becomes a strike fault
そうすると逆断層がストライク断層になります
Is there a way for us to do these things first?
これらのことを最初に行う方法はありますか?
understand its shape
その形を理解する
even academically
学術的にも
If my fault jumps to another fault
私のせいがまた別のせいに飛び火するなら
Or the 1935 Hsinchu-Taichung Earthquake
あるいは 1935 年の新竹・台中地震
It is an earthquake with a greater disaster than 921
921を超える災害を伴う地震です
It is actually three faults
実は3つの欠点がある
From reverse faults to dead faults to strike faults
逆断層からデッド断層、そしてストライク断層まで
How are these mechanisms formed?
これらのメカニズムはどのように形成されるのでしょうか?
so real earthquake science
とてもリアルな地震科学
I don't think it's just about earthquake prediction
地震予知だけではないと思う
real science is understanding
本当の科学は理解することです
How did the fault break
故障はどのようにして壊れたのか
Is there a way for me to know the shape of the fault in advance?
断層の形状を事前に知る方法はありますか？
how to count
数え方
And what happens to him when he moves?
そして、彼が動くと彼はどうなるでしょうか？
We are now finding more and more into fault vibrations
私たちは現在、断層振動の解明を進めています。
You fault away from your location
あなたは自分の場所から離れたところに落ち度がある
when you fault
あなたが失敗したとき
a very long period signal
非常に長い周期の信号
The stunned shout he produced will be introduced later
彼が発した唖然とした叫びは後ほど紹介します
then again
また
How do I know which fault he's moving when
彼がいつ動いているのかをどうやって知ることができますか
Can I simulate it first?
まずはシミュレーションしてもいいでしょうか？
that this morning
今朝のこと
I'm actually at noon today
実は今日はお昼なんです
National Disaster Prevention Science Center
国立防災科学センター
we are talking
私たちは話しています
What we now call digital chaos
私たちが今デジタルカオスと呼んでいるもの
Digital Twin
デジタルツイン
How do I take my Synaryl
シナリールの摂取方法
become a VR
VRになる
Then I can have a solution
そうすれば解決策を見つけることができます
is coming in
入ってくる
that part too
その部分も
digital transformation
デジタル変革
Or in the current big data data
あるいは現在のビッグデータデータでは
work that can be contributed
貢献できる仕事
Then accurately predict the earthquake
そして正確に地震を予測する
That certainly doesn't sound like it has anything to do with the light.
確かに光とは関係ないようですね。
the fact that light i mentioned
私が言った光という事実
it actually increases the resolution
実際に解像度が上がります
let me all countries on this side
すべての国をこちら側にさせてください
Make a more accurate observation component
より正確な観測コンポーネントを作成する
Okay, so if the answer to an earthquake is a more scientific question
さて、地震に対する答えがより科学的な質問であるならば
That's how the earthquake started
地震はこうして始まった
How do I know the earthquake from the first 0.01 seconds
最初の0.01秒から地震をどうやって知ることができるのか
When it starts to bite, how big is it?
噛み始めたらどれくらいの大きさになりますか？
Earthquake it's a random act
地震 それはランダムな行為です
or is it a self-similarity act
それとも自己相似行為ですか
so some people will want to say
だからこう言いたい人もいるだろう
Why should I have an earthquake on a scale 2
なぜマグニチュード2の地震が起きなければならないのか
I'm even on a scale -1 earthquake
スケール-1の地震でも大丈夫です
Because I want to know how the earthquake started
地震がどうやって起こったのか知りたいから
How did that moment come out?
その瞬間はどのようにして生まれましたか？
There are probably a lot of different theories on this part.
この部分についてはおそらくさまざまな理論があるでしょう。
to explore, for example, that it has self-similarity
たとえば、自己相似性があるかどうかを調べます。
or cascadia
またはカスカディア
It actually doesn't know if it will do it
実際にそうなるかどうかは分かりません
It changes as it encounters
出会いで変わる
What if this is the case?
この場合はどうなりますか?
It's hard to predict earthquakes
地震を予知するのは難しい
Which means my earthquake is actually a random act
つまり、私の地震は実際にはランダムな行為であるということです
Of course it's not random
もちろんランダムではありません
It should mean that I did not judge the shape of the entire fault zone
断層帯全体の形状を判断できなかったということになるはずだ
I don't know its strain value
ひずみ値が分かりません
Strength and fault give me resistance
強さと欠点が私に抵抗を与える
who is bigger
誰比較大
I can decide whether I want to move forward and continue to break
前に進むか、壊れ続けるかを決めることができる
still have to stop
まだ止めなければならない
The other way is to say
もう一つの言い方は、
I Earthquake In fact there is one
I 地震は実際にあります
preparatory behavior
準備行動
I am in one place first
まず一つの場所にいます
After accumulating energy
エネルギーを蓄えてから
then start breaking out
それからブレイクアウトを始める
Well, this is of course a scientific challenge.
もちろん、これは科学的な挑戦です。
The role of the science challenge
サイエンスチャレンジの役割
Of course, the previous data were all on the surface.
もちろん、以前のデータはすべて表面上にありました。
or that its data is limited
またはそのデータが制限されている
Farther away from the location of the real small earthquake
実際の小規模地震の発生場所からさらに離れたところ
So there is no way to get it very precisely.
したがって、それを非常に正確に取得する方法はありません。
Not only do I hope that the future's glamorous data
将来の魅力的なデータを期待するだけではありません
is there a way to work on this
これに取り組む方法はありますか
come up with a higher resolution
より高い解像度を思いつく
For example, a few seconds before the beginning
たとえば、始まる数秒前に
this is one second
これは1秒です
or one to six seconds
または 1 ～ 6 秒
Earthquakes of different sizes from 6.7 to 8.7
マグニチュード 6.7 から 8.7 までのさまざまなサイズの地震
You will find it difficult to judge at the beginning
最初は判断するのが難しいと思います
That is to say, we may very well imagine that
つまり、私たちは次のように想像することができます。
It may be relatively slow for small-scale earthquakes
小規模な地震の場合は比較的遅い可能性があります
massive earthquake
大規模地震
In fact, it may be shaking
実際は揺れているかもしれない
no
いいえ
it actually
それは実際に
It might be shaking at first for a small earthquake
小さな地震なら最初は揺れるかもしれない
but it flattened out again
しかしまた平らになった
OK
OK
so tell us
だから教えてください
I want a few seconds from the beginning of the 0.0 signal
0.0信号の始まりから数秒が欲しい
to assess how big the earthquake will be
地震がどれくらいの大きさになるかを評価する
it is challenging
それは挑戦的です
but where is its real challenge
しかし、その本当の課題はどこにあるのか
Because my stations are all above the surface
私のステーションはすべて地表の上にあるので
Above the surface my various noises
表面上の私のさまざまなノイズ
I have a submerged reflection signal
水没した反射信号があります
I have this shockwave zoom in on the grade layer
この衝撃波をグレードレイヤーにズームインしました
i have all kinds of pollution
私はあらゆる種類の汚染を抱えています
That's why we keep referring to earthquakes
だからこそ私たちは地震について言及し続けるのです
I always hope that the deeper the better
深ければ深いほど良いといつも願っています
So you will go to the so-called special police
それでいわゆる特別警察に行くことになる
That's what I just mentioned
それが私が今言ったことです
Although such challenges have been encountered in the past
過去にもそのような課題はあったものの、
but in theory
しかし理論的には
We know that when 3 seconds
3秒後はわかっています
My initial signal can tell me
私の最初の信号が教えてくれる
If I surpass a government like this
このまま政府を超えたら
can tell me about the earthquake
地震について教えてください
At least scale 6 and above
少なくともスケール6以上
So I can start giving earthquake warnings
それで地震警報を出し始めます
Below 6 we may
6未満の場合は可能です
but limited to the west
ただし西側限定
the regulations say
規制にはこう書いてある
Positive degree 5 or scale 6 or above
陽性度5または評価6以上
Early warning of earthquakes with a scale of 5.5 or more
マグニチュード5.5以上の地震に対する緊急警報
ok that job
わかりました、その仕事
This work was published in 2005
この作品は2005年に出版されました
In 2005, the data base behind the important
2005 年に、重要なデータの背後にあるデータベースが
All earthquake data from Taiwan
台湾のすべての地震データ
This is Mr. Wu Yimin
こちらはウー・イーミンさんです
the one just mentioned
今言ったもの
Initial work on the entire orthographic map of PLR
PLR の正投影図全体に関する初期作業
In fact, the whole of Taiwan is used
実は台湾全土が使われている
The most dense data about nearly 20 years
約 20 年分の最も密度の高いデータ
Do the understanding of the whole signal
信号全体を理解する
To understand the possibility of explaining this earthquake warning
この地震警報を説明できる可能性を理解する
Of course, it goes without saying that in the past ten years
もちろん、この10年間で言うまでもなく、
Everyone has become more and more familiar
みんなもどんどん身近になってきましたね
That concept was actually being talked about ten years ago
実はそのコンセプトは10年ほど前から話題になっていたんです
Of course this concept needs a lot
もちろん、このコンセプトには多くのことが必要です
All signals in the latter part
後半のすべての信号
Let all the resources in the latter stage be completed
後の段階のリソースをすべて完了させます
Of course it's not
もちろんそうではありません
doused and wet
びしょ濡れで濡れた
That is to say, when the earthquake warning was issued
つまり、地震警報が発令されたとき
some people have a concept
コンセプトを持っている人もいる
but very accurate
しかし非常に正確です
his concept he mentioned
彼が述べた彼のコンセプト
Earthquake warnings are useless
地震警報は役に立たない
Because you can give early warning somewhere
どこかで早めに警告できるから
He's not that bad anymore
彼はもうそこまで悪くない
OK because your government has decayed
政府は崩壊したから大丈夫
But he is not necessarily accurate
しかし彼は必ずしも正確ではない
I must say, suppose there is an earthquake today
今日地震があったとします。
How many times did the 921 earthquake hit Taipei?
921 地震が台北を何回襲ったでしょうか?
About 10 seconds 20 seconds warning time
警告時間 約10秒 20秒
But Taipei because of its shock wave amplification
しかし、台北は衝撃波が増幅するため、
So you have a moderate amount of forewarning.
したがって、適度な量の事前警告が得られます。
But not to mention high-speed rail, MRT
高速鉄道やMRTは言うまでもありませんが、
These things are already
こういったものはすでに
directly already in use
直接すでに使用されている
But this concept is not
しかし、この概念はそうではありません
his concept
彼のコンセプト
It is generally challenging the concept of earthquake early warning
一般的に緊急地震速報の概念に挑戦しています
nothing wrong
何も間違っていません
That is to say, my real challenge is
つまり、私の本当の課題は
I On site Erling Undead
I オンサイト アーリングアンデッド
How do I make my blind spot smaller and smaller
死角をどんどん小さくするにはどうすればよいですか
Which means I'll build an earthquake signal in.
つまり、地震信号を設置するということです。
I have to have three stations to receive
受信するには3局必要です
So, I passed it through three stations
ということで、3つの駅を通過しました
You are at a depth of 10 kilometers
あなたは深さ10キロメートルにいる
It's already going to cost three stations
もう3駅分かかるよ
two or three seconds
2、3秒
Not to mention I also need data processing
言うまでもなくデータ処理も必要です
I want to go out again
また出かけたい
you want the signal to come in
信号が入ってくるようにしたいのですか
You throw it out after you get it
手に入れたら捨てるんだよ
Then the whole time is delayed
そうなると全体の時間が遅れてしまいます
So there is a big blind spot
つまり大きな盲点があるのです
That's about 30 kilometers, 50 kilometers
それは約30キロ、50キロです
That is to say, if Jingyuan is right next to you
つまり、もしJingyuanがあなたの隣にいたら
you have no chance of getting
あなたには得るチャンスがありません
time to get warning
警告を受ける時間
Of course we are developing now
もちろん現在開発中です
Unsee Aluminium Wondering 4
アルミニウムの不思議 4
Earthquake 10 kilometers deep in the ground
地下10キロメートルの地震
You may still have 1 2 seconds
まだ 1 ～ 2 秒あるかもしれません
Effective
効果的
But this is not from the weather bureau
でもこれは気象庁からの情報ではありません
Regional Earthquake Early Warning
地域別緊急地震速報
Bureau of Meteorology We are now receiving
気象庁より受付中です
Earthquake warnings issued by Meteorological Bureau are regional earthquake warnings
気象庁が発表する地震警報は地方地震警報です
just after some distance
少し離れたところに
you will get an earthquake warning
地震警報が届きます
but you are there
でもあなたはそこにいる
For example, the Ikegami earthquake
例えば池上地震。
you are on the pool
あなたはプールにいる
You have no chance of getting an earthquake warning signal
地震警報を受信する可能性はありません
because time is too late
時間が遅すぎるから
Then our real challenge now is
それでは、私たちの今の本当の課題は、
How do I future is there a chance to use
今後どうやって使用する機会がありますか
this bright signal
この明るい信号
I can make the blind spot smaller and smaller
死角をどんどん小さくできる
I can't say with absolute certainty that it's perfectly fine
絶対大丈夫とは言い切れませんが、
But because the challenge is great
しかし、挑戦は素晴らしいので、
like me this morning ourselves
今朝の私のように、私たち自身も
Guru Meeting is doing Aluminum Wondering of AI
Guru Meeting は AI のアルミニウム ワンダリングを行っています
just mentioned
先ほど述べた
It seems that after the Chigami earthquake
千上地震の後だそうです
nearby
近く
Those stations are all disconnected
それらのステーションはすべて切断されています
So even if my data processing site is good
たとえデータ処理サイトが良好だったとしても
Well done Fly
よくやったフライ
Actually the earthquake shook it and it disconnected
実は地震で揺れて断線してしまいました
So we can't do it
だからそれはできない
So I just introduced to you
ということで、先ほどご紹介させていただきました
Real-Time Moment Tensors made by Mr. Li Xiancong
Li Xiancong 氏が作成したリアルタイム モーメント テンソル
So we later have many versions that are
したがって、その後、次のような多くのバージョンが作成されます。
Scale 6 scale 5 both work fine
スケール 6 スケール 5 両方とも正常に動作します
because it's all online
すべてオンラインだから
A scale of 7 has several stations that may be
7 のスケールには、次のようなステーションがいくつかあります。
Will Centralize or disconnect
集中化または切断します
So we mentioned at that time that I really wanted to challenge
だから、その時は本当に挑戦したいと話しました。
An earthquake with a magnitude of 8.0 in the Ryukyu Trench is in the open sea
琉球海溝でマグニチュード8.0の地震が外海で発生
Then we're going to use the Japanese signal
次に、日本の信号を使用します。
Signals used in the Philippines
フィリピンで使われている信号
Signals used in Mainland China
中国本土で使用される信号
to skip Taiwan
台湾をスキップする
Then how do we have an instant signal exchange
では、どうすれば信号を瞬時に交換できるのでしょうか？
Then this is also the Earth Institute of the Chinese Academy
それから、ここも中国アカデミーの地球研究所です
Cooperate with many international
多くの国際機関と協力する
That is, I have direct data exchange
つまり、直接データ交換を行っています
can keep me on our island
私を島に留めておくことができる
In the case of a large-scale earthquake and power outages
大規模地震や停電の場合
i can still function
私はまだ機能できます
If you have the opportunity to compare yourself
自分と比べてみる機会があれば
will know
わかるでしょう
During the 921 earthquake, the COFCO radio station collapsed and nothing was left
921地震の際、COFCOラジオ局は倒壊し何も残らなかった
I remember back then that I still had to talk over the phone
当時はまだ電話で話さなければならなかったのを覚えています
Let my Japanese friends tell me what happened
日本人の友達に何が起こったのか教えてください
Then as long as there is power, grab the signal and start analyzing it.
その後、電力がある限り、信号を取得して分析を開始します。
Of course, the experience of 921 taught our country a lot
もちろん、921の経験は我が国に多くのことを教えました
So we are now in the Ministry of Science and Technology
それで私たちは今科学技術省にいます
When the National Science and Technology Council does these tasks, it will mention that
国家科学技術会議がこれらの任務を遂行する際には、次のことに言及します。
How do I ensure critical infrastructure is not compromised
重要なインフラが侵害されていないことを確認するにはどうすればよいですか
So the simulation of the large-scale earthquake we just talked about
それで、先ほど話した大規模地震のシミュレーションです。
I want to know where the Taipower tower is
タイパワータワーの場所を知りたい
gas it won't it leak because
ガス漏れないから
It's just that if there is a leak, it will cause a fire.
ただ、漏れがあると火災の原因になります。
Are our facilities complete in this part?
この部分の設備は充実していますか?
Here's what we're doing with massive earthquakes
大地震に対する私たちの取り組みは次のとおりです
Well, of course, this is very early work.
もちろん、これは非常に初期の作品です。
But I think it's worth watching directly with you
でも、あなたと一緒に直接見る価値があると思います
For example, during the 921 earthquake
たとえば、921 年の地震のとき
You can see that the earthquake took ten or twenty seconds
地震が10秒か20秒かかったことがわかります
Seismic waves began to spread to Taichung
地震の波が台中に広がり始めた
The government here in Fengyuan is very big
ここ豊原の政府は非常に大きいです
it breaks from south to north
南から北に切れます
So there is a relatively large government in the north
北部には比較的大きな政府がある
You will see that Taipei currently has no
台北には現在何もないことがわかります。
So we have about 40 seconds
ということで、40秒くらいあります
Early warning to Taipei
台北への早期警告
Of course, this concept is already underway.
もちろん、この構想はすでに進行中です。
I just wanna say it's a really good
本当に良いものだと言いたいだけです
The demo lets you see what the concept of early warning is
デモでは、早期警告の概念がどのようなものかを確認できます。
Of course I don't now
もちろん今はしてない
I need a signal received
信号を受信する必要があります
and then send out these times
そしてこれらの時間を送信します
But in fact these are already being resolved
しかし実際にはこれらはすでに解決されています
Then of course when you arrive in Taipei City
そしてもちろん台北市に到着したら
Use three-dimensional transmission in this management line
この管理ラインでは3次元伝送を使用します
It is very important to calculate this information
これらの情報を計算することは非常に重要です
Of course there are layers of problems in the Taipei Basin
もちろん、台北盆地には問題が山積している
These signals need to be higher and higher resolution
これらの信号はますます高解像度になる必要があります
We can see the seismic waves inside the basin
盆地内の地震波が見える
how does it shake and how long does it shake
どのように揺れるのか、どのくらい揺れるのか
So you'll talk about when Earthquake Island comes
それで、地震島が来るときについて話すでしょう
how long did you shake
どのくらい震えましたか
because the longer you shake
震える時間が長ければ長いほど
Of course there will be some disasters
もちろん災害もあるだろうけど
How long can I shake it
どれくらい振ることができますか
This matter is also included in the information
この件もインフォメーションに記載しております
This is what I personally consider my second generation seismic domain
これが私が個人的に考える第 2 世代の地震領域です。
I hope my second-generation earthquake warning is based on the floor level and the degree of shaking
第二世代の地震警報が床の高さと揺れの程度に基づいていることを願っています
It can be included in the concept of earthquake early warning
緊急地震速報の概念に含めることができる
These tasks are actually the basic information behind
これらのタスクは実際には背後にある基本情報です
high-resolution basic data
高解像度基本データ
This is also back to the bright
こちらも明るさに戻りました
At that time, we hoped that several scenes in the Taipei Basin
当時、私たちは台北盆地のいくつかの風景を望んでいた。
I can also play bright
明るく弾くこともできる
I can parse the whole related construct more clearly
関連する構造全体をより明確に解析できます
the whole job of course
もちろん仕事全体
this is what i just mentioned
これは私が今言ったことです
We started 10 years ago
私たちは10年前に始めました
It is the Taiwan earthquake model under the framework of the Taiwan Earthquake Science Center
台湾地震科学センターの枠組みによる台湾地震モデルです
Cross-departmental committees cast all these tasks in
部門を超えた委員会がこれらすべてのタスクを投入します
For example, the Shanjiao fault that everyone is familiar with in the Taipei Basin
例えば、台北盆地にある誰もが知っている山角断層
that in order
それは順番に
In fact, September of this year is the Xin-Chen Fault, which is on the Hsinchu side.
実は今年の9月は新竹側にある新鎮断層です。
So your drill in September is also calculated by us.
したがって、9 月の訓練も当社によって計算されます。
That is, the exercise in September will focus on new and old faults
つまり、9月の演習では新旧の断層に焦点を当てることになる。
Then next year will focus on Chiayi
そして来年は嘉義に焦点を当てます
That is, we will continue to work with ministries related to the Ministry of the Interior
つまり、今後も内務省関係省庁と連携してまいります。
to get to know them
彼らを知るために
requirements on the application
アプリケーションの要件
If you want to be accurate
正確に知りたければ
That is to say, you are talking about the simulation of seismic waves.
つまり、地震波のシミュレーションのことを言っているわけです。
Since ten or twenty years ago
十年か二十年前から
very, very many people are developing
非常に多くの人が開発を行っています
Then of course we mentioned that
それからもちろん、私たちはそれについて言いました
simulation
シミュレーション
It is already difficult to write programs for agents
エージェント向けのプログラムを書くのはすでに困難です
After you build someone else's program
他人のプログラムをビルドした後
You just enter and then output
入力して出力するだけです
Then let me tell you that you are garbage in garbage out
それなら、あなたはゴミの中のゴミだと言わせてください
who knows right
誰が正しく知っていますか
So the simulation at that time was actually
それで、そのときのシミュレーションは実際には
It took a lot of effort to convince that
それを納得させるのに大変な努力が必要だった
ours is
私たちのものは
of scientific value is
科学的価値があるのは、
validation came out
検証が出てきました
Because of too many different simulations
さまざまなシミュレーションが多すぎるため
can come in
入ることができます
So we have to be very accurate
したがって、非常に正確である必要があります
I know that the data I entered is
私が入力したデータは
is reliable
信頼できる
We spent a lot of time on that part
私たちはその部分に多くの時間を費やしました
With earthquake engineering and with national units
地震工学と国家単位
do this communication
このコミュニケーションを行う
So we can take all the criteria
したがって、すべての基準を採用できます
list them all
それらをすべてリストアップしてください
Then I just mentioned the structure of the entire basin
それから、先ほど盆地全体の構造についてお話しました。
We still have certain limitations in resolution
解像度にはまだ一定の制限があります
So my current signal is about 0.5Hz for 2 seconds
つまり、現在の信号は2秒間約0.5Hzです
5 seconds but the real one seems to be 1Hz to 10Hz
5秒ですが実際は1Hz～10Hzのようです
Then your resolution must be very high, and the calculation program must be very large.
その場合、解像度は非常に高く、計算プログラムは非常に大きくなければなりません。
Then we certainly hope that the future fiber will allow us to do this work
そして、将来のファイバーによってこの作業が可能になることを私たちは確かに期待しています。
push the structural resolution of my basin to become clearer
私の盆地の構造的解像度をますます明確に押し上げます
The other teacher who just talked about cooperation, Mr. Huang Xinhua
先ほど協力について話したもう一人の先生、黄新華先生
he is making mountains
彼は山を作っている
When I use optical fiber, is it shaken by an earthquake?
光ファイバーを使用している場合、地震などで揺れることはありますか？
Or when it rains heavily, there will be landslides
または、大雨が降ると土砂崩れが発生します
Can I monitor the display of landslides
地滑りの表示を監視できますか
That's also supported by the plan of the Hospital of Traditional Chinese Medicine.
それは中医薬病院の計画によっても裏付けられています。
we're doing the big death part
私たちは大死のパートをやっています
In addition to earthquakes, there are also extended disasters such as landslides.
地震だけでなく、土砂災害などの広域災害も発生します。
For example, there are basin structures but no basin structures
例えば、盆地構造はあるが盆地構造は存在しない。
You can see clearly that this is
これははっきりとわかります
When there is a structure in the Taipei Basin
台北盆地に建造物がある場合
You will see the seismic waves when the ship lands
船が着陸すると地震波が見えます
He just showed you
彼はちょうどあなたに見せたばかりです
This is Dr. Constitutionalist's calculation.
これが護憲派博士の計算だ。
his resonant behavior in
彼の共鳴行動
but you will see say
しかし、あなたは言うでしょう
Because this is a triangle fault
ここは三角断層だから
which we provided to the Ministry of the Interior
私たちが内務省に提供したもの
You sometimes mentioned on the news that
時々ニュースで言ってましたが、
so-and-so member or whoever mentioned said
誰々のメンバー、または言及した人が言いました
If an earthquake with a magnitude of 6.4 occurs in Taipei,
台北でマグニチュード6.4の地震が起きたら、
How many houses will collapse
何軒の家が倒壊するだろうか
how many people were injured
何人が負傷しましたか
That's actually what we calculated
それは実際に私たちが計算したものです
Give it to NCDR to see their entire
NCDR に渡して全体を確認してください
the structure of the house
家の構造
then start pushing
それから押し始めます
Internal reinforcement
內政補強
even new building codes
新しい建築基準法であっても
Then I think these tasks are slowly going on.
その後、これらの作業は徐々に進んでいくと思います。
Then you see it's still biting
それから、まだ噛んでいるのがわかります
This part is over
この部分は終わりです
so this is
それでこれは
Fine Velocity Structure
微速度構造
allows us to calculate more precisely
より正確に計算できるようになります
so i've been thinking
それで私は考えてきました
From 5 to have is relatively simple
5から持つまでは比較的簡単です
but from there to better
しかしそこからより良い方向へ
I think everyone has experience with this challenge
誰もがこの課題に直面した経験があると思います
You can pass the test to 80 points
80点までテストに合格できます
you score 80 to 90
あなたは80点から90点を獲得します
Efforts can also be achieved
努力も実現できる
But you're going from 99 to 100
でもあなたは99から100へ行くのです
1 point for this
これで1ポイント
In fact, it takes a lot of effort
実はかなりの労力がかかるんです
So now we actually want to go from 80 to 90
それで、今私たちは実際に 80 から 90 に行きたいのです
slowly push forward to better
より良い方向へゆっくりと前進する
Is there a chance for this signal first?
このシグナルが最初に発生する可能性はありますか?
let's do this
これをやろう
Of course it goes into the process
もちろんその過程に入ります
This is the time to enter section 921
今こそ第 921 条に入る時です
nearby station
近くの駅
These are protected from wind bridges, shot collapse, and so on.
これらは風橋やショットの崩壊などから保護されます。
The most important thing is this very signal from the Cheung Chau flag
最も重要なことは、まさに長州旗からの信号です。
This speed signal is a possible way
この速度信号は可能な方法です
A Cheung Chau flag signal
長州旗信号
Push the house down
家を押し倒す
How did the Cheung Chau flag signal come from?
長洲国旗信号はどのようにして生まれたのでしょうか?
At that time we published
その時に出版したのが
It was our TCTP at that time
それが当時の私たちのTCTPでした
We publish in some of the top
トップの一部に掲載しております
Journals to discuss
議論する雑誌
how the hell did it happen
一体どうやって起こったのか
For example, it's actually when an earthquake occurs
例えば、実際に地震が起きたときです。
it can also accelerate
加速することもできる
a speed
速度
But when it reaches its maximum speed
しかし最高速度に達すると
My displacement continues to slide forward
私の変位は前方に滑り続けます
Because my section contains
私のセクションには次の内容が含まれているため、
If it is a very detailed
非常に詳しい内容であれば
If the ring keeps slipping
リングが滑り続ける場合
My minerals and time-lapse
私のミネラルとタイムラプス
In fact, particles down to the nanometer
実はナノメートルまでの粒子が
When it comes to nano particles
ナノ粒子といえば
I fact many thermodynamic influences
実際、多くの熱力学的影響がある
my big doubts arise when i have
大きな疑問が湧いてくるのは、
smoperturization
不純物化
After letting my faults open
自分の欠点を開いた後
I'll slide forward even bigger
もっと大きく前に滑ってみます
that this part we are not
この部分は私たちではないということ
There is a way for casting
キャストする方法もある
is that I can figure out that
それは私が理解できるということです
if a scale
スケールなら
When reaching 7.0
7.0に達すると
behavior like this happens
このような行為が起こる
Then I for my disaster prevention work
それから私は防災業務に
it is very important to understand
理解することが非常に重要です
But science is more important
しかし科学はもっと重要です
At that time in 9.1
9.1の当時
Many scholars come to Taiwan
多くの学者が台湾に来ます
He explored why an earthquake
彼はなぜ地震が起こるのかを調べた
can have so much energy
とても多くのエネルギーを持つことができます
Theoretically, the hard force generated by the crust
理論的には、地殻によって発生する硬い力は
Shouldn't be that hard
そんなに難しくないはず
In fact it's all kinetic
実際、それはすべて運動的なものです
It is a passive kinetic behavior
それは受動的な運動行動です
of course now
もちろん今
Dynamics simulation can handle this matter
ダイナミクスシミュレーションはこの問題に対処できます
is in the stage of development
発展段階にあります
that kind of signal
そういう信号
we asked for advice
私たちはアドバイスを求めました
All scale 6.7 and above
すべてのスケール 6.7 以上
Like the 921G earthquake version 7.3 and the version 7.2 earthquake
像921G地震7.3 版生地震7.2
The Landes earthquake 7.2 is a large-scale earthquake
ランデス地震 7.2 はいずれも大規模地震
But everyone should still remember the Meinong earthquake in 2016
しかし、誰もが2016年の美濃地震をまだ覚えているはずです
Scale 6.4 Same as a Long period of ground motion
スケール 6.4 長周期地震動と同じ
This Long period of ground motion is no longer a
この長い周期の地震動はもはや
think it may have happened by accident
それは偶然起こったのかもしれないと思う
We now feel more and more that it is a physical phenomenon
私たちは今、それが物理的な現象であるとますます感じています
it is a physical phenomenon
それは物理現象です
It's just that the seismic instruments were not placed so densely before.
ただ、以前は耐震機器がそれほど密集して配置されていなかっただけです。
so no detection
だから検出されない
That's not to mention whether the future light may have the opportunity to see more
未来の光がもっと見る機会があるかどうかは言うまでもありません
That's why I say earthquake science is an observational science
私が地震科学は観測科学だと言うのはこのためです
Had a lot of conversations with everyone in the engineering world
エンジニアリング業界の皆さんとたくさんの会話をしました
The engineering world used to tell me back then
エンジニアリングの世界は当時私にこう言っていました。
Of course we have an earthquake culture preschool attempt
もちろん、地震文化幼稚園の試みもあります
He told me, Mr. Meng, you gave too much shock
彼は私に言いました、孟さん、あなたはショックを与えすぎました
This way you can find a way to make it smaller
そうすれば小さくする方法が見つかる
Then I thought about how to think about it
じゃあどうやって考えるか考えてみた
This is data, I can't think of a way
これはデータです、方法が思いつきません
it is data
それはデータです
But in terms of data, they mean
しかし、データの観点から言えば、
In our previous earthquake engineering, it was
以前の地震工学では、
More than about magnitude 5
マグニチュード5程度以上
my house fell down
私の家は倒れました
In fact we found
実際に私たちは見つけました
A Taiwan egg with a magnitude of 5 may be a well-built house
マグニチュード5の台湾の卵は立派に建てられた家かもしれない
That's not all down
それだけではありません
So something actually
それで、実際には何か
I need to do a lot of dialogue and exploration.
たくさんの対話と探索を行う必要があります。
So from the beginning I thought
だから最初から思ってた
This Cheung Chau writing signal happened by accident
この長洲の書き込み信号は偶然に起こりました
Up to now, our building regulations in Taiwan
これまでの台湾の建築規制
New building codes have broken into earthquakes
新しい建築基準法は地震を引き起こす
These building codes all come in
これらの建築基準法はすべて適用されます
It was Cheung Chau who wrote the shock
この衝撃を書いたのはチュン・チャウだった
Buildings cannot be built in generations
建物は何世代にもわたって建てることはできません
if you have a private building
民間の建物をお持ちの場合
You must do a special review
特別なレビューを行う必要があります
In fact, this part is included in the laws and regulations.
実はこの部分は法令の中に盛り込まれているのです。
it's my pleasure to have the opportunity
機会があれば嬉しいです
More conversations with engineering
エンジニアリングとのさらなる会話
Then wait a minute and I can introduce you
それでは、ちょっと待ってください、ご紹介します
It is in our MIDASData
それは私たちのMIDASDataにあります
See the phenomenon that Cheung Chau wrote to shake it
長洲氏がそれを揺るがすために書いた現象を見てください
It is actually a fractured structure
実は壊れた構造なのです
caused by the phenomenon
現象によって引き起こされる
Okay, that's what I just said
わかりました、それが私が今言ったことです
The Chigami Earthquake of September 18
9月18日千上地震
It was the earthquake three months ago
3ヶ月前の地震でした
four months
4ヶ月
You may have seen this on the news
ニュースで見たことがあるかもしれません
these bridges fell
これらの橋は落ちた
Semi-11 in that domain is down here
そのドメインのセミ 11 はここにあります
It's just like a very Long period of ground motion
それはちょうど非常に長い周期の地震動のようなものです
caused this disaster
この災害を引き起こした
But some of the same signals are disconnected
ただし、同じ信号の一部が切断されています
That's what I mentioned to the weather bureau
気象庁にはそう言いました
We want a Resilient Society
私たちはレジリエントな社会を目指します
But we want Resilient Instrumentation
しかし、私たちは復元力のあるインスツルメンテーションを望んでいます
How do we make earthquakes come
どうやって地震を起こすのか
My station on the nearest fault won't be disconnected
最も近い障害にある私のステーションは切断されません
Because many of my research materials need near-fault data
私の研究資料の多くには故障に近いデータが必要であるため、
then this is a challenge
それならこれは挑戦だ
Of course I'm actually in the domain
もちろん、実際にはドメイン内にいます
I set up some stations to see its signal
信号を確認するためにいくつかのステーションを設定しました
good
良い
Okay, so back to the phenomena we were talking about
さて、先ほどの現象に戻ります
of course i want to say
もちろん言いたいです
Why am I talking to the side of the earth?
なぜ私は地球の側に向かって話しているのでしょうか？
Let's mention this key breakthrough plan from the Intermediate People's Court.
中級人民法院によるこの重要な打開計画について触れてみましょう。
because i know it's risky
それは危険だと分かっているから
I will thank the hospital for mentioning that
そう言ってくださった病院には感謝します
The essential
本質的なもの
In fact they understand the risks
実際、彼らはリスクを理解しています
I don't know if it will work
うまくいくかどうかはわかりません
but i think it's an opportunity
でもチャンスだと思う
So I propose to try this
それで私はこれを試してみることを提案します
And at that time, I actually mentioned it to Taipower
その時、私は実際にTaipowerにそのことを話しました。
Carbon dioxide sequesters these things
二酸化炭素はこれらのものを隔離します
But everyone is very conservative about the light
でもみんな光に関してはとても保守的だよ
Then go back to Academia Sinica personally
その後、個人的に中央研究院に戻ります
It is an honor to come to Academia Sinica
中央研究院に来られて光栄です
I know what we're going to do is a lookahead
私たちがやろうとしていることは先読みであることはわかっています
Lead us to Taiwan to challenge a new
私たちを台湾へ導き、新たな挑戦へ
The possibility of scientific development
科学の発展の可能性
that's nice to have a chance we made it
成功するチャンスがあってよかった
So start having a lot of conversations
だからたくさん会話を始めてください
i can't say we succeeded
成功したとは言えません
It should be said that we put it in
入れたというべきでしょう。
The data research is still in the process of writing
データ調査はまだ執筆中です
Then this is us
それでは、これが私たちです
At least we are technically successful
少なくとも技術的には成功している
We even have conversations with Chunghwa Telecom
中華電信とも会話しています
We have a signal that uses Chunghwa Telecom's dialogue
中華電信のダイアログを使用した信号があります
because the real purpose is
なぜなら本当の目的は
All cables in Taiwan
台湾のすべてのケーブル
can become our signal
私たちの信号になることができます
and submarine cables
そして海底ケーブル
But it's a big challenge just take it step by step
しかし、それは大きな挑戦です、一歩ずつ進んでください
When I mentioned it to the hospital, I said
病院にそのことを話したとき、こう言いました。
In addition to these applications
これらのアプリケーションに加えて、
Not to mention the Millennium Fault
ミレニアム断層は言うに及ばず
Probably the most active fault in the world
おそらく世界で最も活断層
Every 70 years
70年ごと
And it moves exactly the same
そして全く同じ動きをします
This was moved in 1951
ここは1951年に移転されました
It's exactly the same as in 2016
2016年と全く同じです
In fact, the Ikegami Fault
実は池上断層
2022 Ikegami earthquake dynamic position
2022年池上地震動的位置
It is exactly the same as the Yuli fault in 1951
1951年の玉里断層と全く同じだ
After the earthquake
地震の後
we've been thinking
私たちは考えてきました
In 1951, this series of steam-scale earthquakes
1951 年にこの一連の水蒸気規模の地震が発生しました。
happen within two months
2か月以内に起こる
what will its condition be like
その状態はどうなるのでしょうか
Seismic activity was high at the time
当時は地震活動が活発だった
So at that time, the chairman of the National Science Council
それで当時、国家学術会議の会長は
At that time, he was the Minister of Science and Technology
当時、彼は科学技術大臣でした
Also hold a meeting with us to understand
理解するために私たちとのミーティングも開催します
What is the nature of its earthquake
その地震の性質は何ですか
Well, Bai Guangguang once said
さて、白光光はかつてこう言いました。
Murren Fault it's already clear
ミューレン断層はすでに明らかです
It is related to the Ryukyu Trench
琉球海溝と関係がある
I just mentioned past life on scale 8.0
先ほどスケール 8.0 での前世について触れました。
Everyone is on the news sometimes
時々みんながニュースに出ます
What century-old politics are you referring to?
何世紀前の政治のことを言ってるんですか？
since 1920
1920年以来
A magnitude 8 earthquake
マグニチュード8の地震
Not to mention its entire fault system is linked together
言うまでもなく、その障害システム全体が相互にリンクされています
If an earthquake warning
地震警報が出たら
It should be said before the earthquake
地震の前に言っておきたい
it is also possible opportunity
それは可能性のある機会でもあります
So not to mention I was hoping to make a
だから言うまでもなく、私はそれを作りたいと思っていました
The biggest experiment is how I put the fiber
最大の実験は繊維をどのように入れるかです
Because the matter of optical fiber has been talked about for two or three years
光ファイバーの話は2～3年前から話題になっているので
In fact, it has been talked about for a long time at home and abroad.
実は、国内外で長い間話題になっていました。
It's just that there has been no actual operation
実際の運用がされていないだけです
my seminar abroad
私の海外セミナー
Of course the time of COVID caused some trouble
もちろん、コロナの時期にはいくつかの問題が発生しました
But when in seminars abroad
しかし、海外でのセミナーでは
listen to me
私の話を聞いて下さい
郭鳳,you have to talk about optical fiber
郭鳳、光ファイバーについて話さなければなりません
I've been thinking that I'm going to smoke this hilarious
これを吸おうと思ってたんだ
You know sometimes scientific research
時々科学研究が行われることをご存知ですか？
still has some feeling of federation
まだ連邦感が残ってる
which thing is particularly popular at a certain time
ある時期に特に人気があるものは何ですか
I want to say I don't want to dare to be popular
あえてモテたくないって言いたい
But I feel more and more
でも、私はますます感じています
it may be the future
それは未来かもしれない
if it is the future
それが未来なら
of course i want to try it
もちろん試してみたいです
what does it look like
それは何に見えますか
let me warm up
温めさせてください
that's to say nothing of me stepping over the fault line
それは私が断層線をまたいでいるということではありません
What does a fault look like?
障害とはどのようなものですか?
that just mentioned
それは今言った
All over the world if I have fiber optics in all locations
すべての場所に光ファイバーがあれば世界中
can i put the fault under the ground
断層を地下に埋めてもいいですか
clearer
より明確な
I'll put the location where I know the fault first.
まずは故障箇所がわかっている箇所を載せておきます。
Is it possible for me to go in the future?
今後行くことは可能でしょうか？
Test other faults first
最初に他の障害をテストしてください
so i
だから私は
This is actually a bit of that
これは実際にはその一部です
already know the answer
すでに答えを知っています
But I still want to know
でもまだ知りたい
What does his answer look like?
彼の答えはどのようなものでしょうか?
so we are here
だから私たちはここにいる
Seven Star Altar Very beautiful Seven Star Altar
七星祭壇 とても美しい七星祭壇
This is the Murren Fault
これがミューレン断層です
We have a well A and a well B
井戸Aと井戸Bがあります
This is the upper plate This is the lower plate
これが上のプレートです これが下のプレートです
I want to be a control group
コントロールグループになりたい
Then in Well C
次にウェルCで
We measure water, air and temperature
水、空気、温度を測定します
Do earthquake light and seismic energy detection
地震光と地震エネルギー検出を行う
the real challenge is
本当の課題は
I'm going to take an optical fiber directly from the surface
表面から直接光ファイバーを取り出します
all the way down
ずっと下まで
700 meters position
700メートル地点
That's a big challenge
それは大きな挑戦です
we have to first
私たちはまずそうしなければなりません
Of course I still have to say
もちろん、まだ言わなければなりません
Then don't talk so much about your heart today.
それなら今日は自分の心のことについてあまり話さないでください。
That
それか
that because of covid
それはコロナのせいだ
I play the first time swing fiber optic
初めて光ファイバーで遊んでいます
To manipulate the light you have to have absolutely no folds
光を操作するにはひだは絶対になくてはなりません
Then if you want 100, it takes a day
100個欲しいなら1日かかる
One hundred to seven hundred meters in one go
一気に100～700メートル
Then our approach is on Jing A's side.
そうすると、私たちのアプローチはJing A側になります。
there's a light starting to come down
光が降り始めている
Go down to the suite
スイートに降りてください
then go up
それから上に行きます
Then cross this scene A and go up and down
そしてこのシーンAを横切って上下に進みます
Go east and go to Qixing
東に進んで七星へ行く
It's where Murren Heights is
ここがミューレンハイツです
In fact, the fire department in Hualien is going to connect us now
実際、花蓮の消防署は私たちを結びつけたいと考えています。
Do disaster prevention education
防災教育をしましょう
Then go back to Scene A
そしてシーンAに戻ります
I use Chunghwa Telecom for this section of blue
この青いセクションには中華電信を使用しています
We had a long discussion with Chunghwa Telecom
中華電信と長い議論をしました
So they now use our Chunghwa Telecom
そこで彼らは今、中華電信を使用しています。
For our work, they are going to fight for Taiwan's sustainable award
私たちの仕事のために、彼らは台湾の持続可能な賞を求めて戦うつもりです
The first time we talked to him
初めて彼と話したとき
How to put business work and forward-looking science together
ビジネスの仕事と先進的な科学をどのように組み合わせるか
Thanks to Lin Qingren and Huang Xinhua
林清仁氏と黄新華氏に感謝
They put a lot of effort into dialogue
彼らは対話にとても力を入れています
Chunghwa Telecom
中華電信
The main reason is that there are many houses here
一番の理由はここに家がたくさんあるから
It is also impossible for us to dig any location
任意の場所を掘ることも不可能です
Chunghwa Telecom
中華電信
Then he closes and continues up and down
それから彼は閉じて上下を続けます
Then go to Qixingtan to cross the whole border
それから七星潭に行き、国境全体を越えます
So we become a three-dimensional
だから私たちは三次元になる
monitoring of the entire signal
信号全体のモニタリング
We are now writing our article
私たちは今記事を書いています
But we in China say that I will extend my salary
しかし、私たち中国では、給料を延長すると言います。
The salary extension of this special policeman actually took a lot of effort
この特別警察官の給与延長には実は大変な労力がかかった
Well of course this is a long story to tell
もちろん、これを話すのは長い話です
If you are interested
もし興味があれば
That reporter has been following us for two years
その記者は2年間私たちを追いかけています
So his reporter wrote a very good article last year
それで彼の記者は昨年非常に良い記事を書きました
And China TV News Magazine
そして中国テレビニュースマガジン
And Dong Sen has come to make these documentaries
そしてドン・センはこれらのドキュメンタリーを作るために来ました
So if you are interested
それで、興味があるなら
You can read their reports
彼らのレポートを読むことができます
I just mentioned that, of course I can't say
先ほども言いましたが、もちろん言えません
Hit it out of nowhere
どこからともなく殴る
Explain that at the beginning, of course, many policies
もちろん、最初は多くのポリシーがあることを説明します
This is after we must have done a lot of thinking
これは私たちがたくさん考えた後だったに違いありません
I need to know that I'm actually certain that I'm going to fight
私は実際に戦うつもりであると確信していることを知る必要がある
about my location
私の居場所について
But it's not just talking about fighting
しかし、それは単に戦うことについて話しているわけではありません
People may not be willing to let us fight, right?
人々は私たちを戦わせたくないかもしれませんね？
And then again in such a beautiful place as Qixingtan
そしてまた七星潭のような美しい場所に
I went there and thought Chihsingtan is really, really beautiful.
そこに行って、七星潭は本当に本当に美しいと思いました。
We hope to combine this work with sightseeing
この仕事と観光を組み合わせていきたいと考えています
Combined with disaster prevention education
防災教育との組み合わせ
Therefore, in the selection of the whole field
したがって、分野全体の選択においては、
we spent a year
私たちは一年を過ごしました
Convince Hualien County Government
花蓮県政府を説得する
Disaster Prevention Office Central Disaster Prevention Office
防災室 中央防災室
Our director went to Hualien and so on
監督が花蓮などに行ってきました
do a lot of public hearings
公聴会をたくさん行う
Tell local residents why we do this work
私たちがこの仕事をする理由を地域住民に伝えてください
It took us a year
1年かかりました
all clerical visits
すべての事務訪問
I am grateful that is the House of Representatives
それが衆議院であることに感謝します
some executives of key breakthroughs
重要な進歩を遂げた一部の幹部
and hospital administrators
と病院管理者
help with a lot of work
たくさんの仕事を手伝う
Chunghwa Telecom
還有中華電信
Chunghwa Telecom told us at the beginning that we would
中華電信は当初、我々にこう言いました。
You have to charge us 300,000,500,000 a year
年間300,000,500,000の請求が必要です
1.5 million in three years
3年で150万
I want to say we don't have the funds
資金がないって言いたいんだ
So we convinced a lot
それで私たちは大いに納得しました
tell him why
彼に理由を教えてください
what do you think about this
あなたはこのことについてどう思いますか
Chunghwa Telecom
中華電信
is also worth it
それも価値があります
So it took a lot of work to have this conversation
ですから、この会話をするのには大変な労力がかかりました
So thanks to the many teams and all the observations in the field
多くのチームと現場での観察に感謝します
This whole thing took about a year to start earning
収益を上げ始めるまでに約 1 年かかりました
Start earning, of course the key is of course very big
稼ぎ始めます、もちろん鍵は非常に大きいです
is when we reach earning generation
私たちが稼ぐ世代になるとき
I have been worrying together all the time
ずっと一緒に悩んできた
We took the exam for two months
私たちは2ヶ月間試験を受けました
When I took the exam, I thought it was great.
試験を受けた時はすごいと思いました。
It should be that we reach Earn Generation
Earn Generationに到達するはずです
But at the same time, I feel that I can't make money, what should I do?
でも同時に「稼げない、どうしたらいいの？」とも感じます。
At that time, it was said that the hospital's plan was to talk about it.
その際、病院側の方針として話し合ったという。
Mr. Mao, your knowledge rate is too low
マオさん、知識率低すぎます
You need to finish it quickly
早く終わらせないといけないよ
So there's a lot of dialogue probably with the colonial side
したがって、おそらく植民地側と多くの対話が行われています
or the office on this side of the courtyard
または中庭のこちら側のオフィス
Quick Technician does a lot of dialogue
クイックテクニシャンは多くの対話を行います
i can't give up
諦められない
But it was impossible for me to give to the money-making company the year before last
でも一昨年は金儲けの会社に寄付するのは無理だった
I have to be in place before I can give
与える前にその場にいなければなりません
Then this is fiber optic
それから、これは光ファイバーです
too much on this story
この話には多すぎる
I will tell the result directly
結果は直接お伝えします
This is the fiber that actually runs from the UK
これは実際にイギリスから流れているファイバーです
COVID is very serious
新型コロナウイルスは非常に深刻です
So when his instrument comes
だから彼の楽器が来たら
We put it in the middle of the situation for two months
2ヶ月間そのままにしておきました
no one dares to touch it
誰もそれに触れようとしません
The British company is coming
イギリスの会社が来る
found the company
会社を見つけた
We've spent all the money the madman cleared.
私たちは狂人が払ったお金をすべて使ってしまいました。
It's impossible to make money from negative companies
ネガティブな会社からお金を稼ぐことは不可能です
so by us young people
だから私たち若者によって
Ph.D. Dr. Gu Jinshang
博士 古今上博士
And these drilling teams
そしてこれらの掘削チームは
step by step to design
段階的にデザインする
Because when I take the whole case
だって、ケース全体を取ると
fiber next to me
私の隣のファイバー
I can't fold the fiber
ファイバーを折りたためない
But I want very good copying
しかし、私は非常に優れたコピーが欲しいです
Then I'm going to fix it really well
じゃあ、しっかり治していきますね
So the whole technique has been practiced N hundred times
つまり、このテクニック全体は N 百回も練習されたことになる
That is, every step we take every step to achieve
つまり、達成するために私たちが行うすべてのステップ
Then I thank the British team
それからイギリスチームに感謝します
at christmas time
クリスマスの時期に
he is video chatting with us
彼は私たちとビデオチャットしています
Our optical fiber was launched in December last year
当社の光ファイバーは昨年12月に発売されました
It should be the year before last
一昨年のはずです
December 31
12月31日
That's really the first signal coming in
それが本当に最初に入ってくる信号です
is January 1, 2022
は 2022 年 1 月 1 日です
We are all welcoming the sunrise at Qixingtan
みんなで七星潭の日の出を歓迎します
In fact, there is no place to live
実は住むところがない
Because Qixingtan is full
七星潭がいっぱいだから
So we are in fact
それで私たちは実際に
Everyone find a place by themselves
誰もが自分で場所を見つけます
to finish but just happy
終わりますが、ただ幸せです
When the signal is completed
信号が完了すると
But Taiwan is not worried about earthquakes at all, the signal will come in immediately
でも台湾は地震の心配は全くなく、すぐに電波が入ります
ok then this is
わかりました、それではこれです
Scene A on January 1, 2022
2022 年 1 月 1 日のシーン A
Scene B on June 2, 2022
2022 年 6 月 2 日のシーン B
In other words, June 2, 2022
つまり、2022 年 6 月 2 日
Our entire circuit is complete.
回路全体が完成しました。
That is, as soon as we put it down,
つまり、置いたらすぐに、
Must be all 24 hours at once so
24 時間同時に行う必要があるので、
And put all the wiring together
そして全ての配線をまとめて、
is the completion of our entire signal
これで信号全体が完成します
follow the operation
操作に従ってください
I think it's really about the signal of an earthquake.
まさに地震の前兆だと思います。
That's what it said
そういうことだった
Yes, all the work, is it worth it?
はい、すべての仕事、それだけの価値がありますか?
I've actually been thinking
実は考えてたんです
for what
何のために
my signal is beautiful
私の信号は美しいです
At that time this was
その時はこれでした
You see, it starts to go down on January 1st.
ご存知のとおり、1月1日から下がり始めます。
I face the computer every day
私は毎日パソコンと向き合っています
The earthquake on January 7, an earthquake in Taichung
1月7日の地震、台中地震
I think earthquakes are really good
地震は本当に良いことだと思う
Because it has a scale of 4.7, it is neither too big nor too small, and it is very deep.
スケール4.7なので大きすぎず小さすぎず、とても奥が深いです。
So its signal to our station is almost vertically rounded
したがって、私たちのステーションへの信号はほぼ垂直に丸くなっています
I saw this signal and thought it was so beautiful
この信号を見てとても美しいと思いました
but i mean earthquake repair
でも、私は地震の修理を意味します
so i feel very beautiful
だから私はとても美しいと感じます
This is from the ground to the ground
これは地面から地面までです
then it is symmetrical
それなら対称です
I just told me to go down
降りろって言っただけだよ
then up again
それからまた上がる
you can see it's symmetrical
対称的であることがわかります
then you can see
そうすればわかります
This is a two-second signal
これは 2 秒間の信号です
I can see when the batch comes in
バッチがいつ到着するかがわかります
Then I've seen some disturbances in these
それから私はこれらの中でいくつかの混乱を見てきました
These disturbances are seismic zones
これらの擾乱は地震帯です
fault zone
断層帯
then i see some facial zone
それから顔のゾーンが見えます
I am one and then how does the seismic wave reflect the selective shot
私もその一人ですが、地震波は選択的なショットをどのように反射しますか
I can see everything clearly
すべてがはっきりと見えます
Even so
たとえそうであっても
I'm still staring at it in a daze
まだ茫然とそれを見つめている
So what can you do?
それで、何ができるでしょうか？
Ok
Ok
You guys beautiful and then
あなたたちは美しい、そしてそれから
so I've been thinking about it
だから私はそれについて考えてきました
But there are more and more important discoveries
しかし、さらに重要な発見があります
For example this is the same as an earthquake
例えばこれは地震と同じです
Of course I drew it in a better way
もちろんもっといい感じに描きましたよ
you can see
見ることができます
4 meters, sorry, forgot to mention
4メートル、ごめんなさい、言い忘れてました
we are one
私たちは一つです
We have a resolution of 4 meters
解像度は4メートルです
Then the signal is 1000Hz
その場合、信号は1000Hzです
So it has a very, very large amount of data
したがって、非常に大量のデータが含まれています
Of course we have to treat it as
もちろん、それを次のように扱う必要があります
When sample to 200Hz
200Hzまでサンプリングした場合
Then we also follow what we get
そして私たちも得たものに従います
The grid center of our courtyard
私たちの中庭のグリッドセンター
Thanks to Mr. Liang Wenzhong
梁文中氏に感謝
They have collaborated many times before
彼らはこれまで何度もコラボしてきた
on some basis of
何らかの根拠に基づいて
Do this same conversation with the grid center
グリッドセンターと同じ会話を行います
Our data is sent to the grid center
データはグリッドセンターに送信されます
Then our grid center has
すると、グリッドセンターは
When we analyze data
データを分析するとき
Put data directly from the center of the grid
グリッドの中心から直接データを配置します
extract
萃取出来
then this part is
そうするとこの部分は
Collaboration between many units in the hospital
病院内の多くの部門間の連携
then we
それから私たち
An earthquake is coming up from below
下から地震がやってくる
You can see this signal below
この信号は以下で確認できます
It's standing in a row, it's quite beautiful
並んでいてとても綺麗です
After reaching the fault, it was disturbed
障害に到達した後、障害が発生しました
then you have surface reflection
そうすれば表面反射が起こります
Then your batch comes in
それからあなたのバッチが到着します
your signal
あなたの信号
The structure of each signal and formation
各信号機とフォーメーションの構造
Can simulate one by one
1つずつシミュレーションできる
for real
実際に
don't do any analysis at all
まったく分析を行わない
You can see where it says I'm close to the fault line
断層線に近いと書いてあるのがわかりますね
The whole government is amplified
政府全体が増幅される
remember what i just mentioned
私が今言ったことを思い出してください
Cheung Chau flag shakes near fault
長州国旗が揺れる原因付近
In this example it is
この例では、
you don't move anything
あなたは何も動かない
you actually see it is fault behavior
実際にはそれが障害動作であることがわかります
it doesn't happen randomly either
それはランダムに起こるわけでもない
As long as your fault zone is certain
断層帯が確実である限り
The difference in material
素材の違い
it produces a government amplification
それは政府による増幅を引き起こす
fault zone
断層帯
not very clear
あまり明確ではない
about 20 meters
約20メートル
Then this is a fault zone only 20 meters
そうすると、ここはわずか20メートルの断層帯です
So, if you take Jinxia earthquake today
では、今日の金夏地震を例にとると、
you'll miss it too
あなたもそれを見逃すでしょう
because after you cross the fault zone
断層帯を越えた後だから
It behaves exactly the same
その行動には一貫性がある
So you can only rely on this very high resolution
したがって、信頼できるのはこの非常に高い解像度だけです
Only then can you know if your long fingers have been magnified
そうして初めて、あなたの長い指が拡大されたかどうかを知ることができます
Did you really see the Yanpan signal?
本当にヤンパン信号を見ましたか？
Going back to the beginning of the earthquake just mentioned
先ほどの地震の発端に戻ります。
0.01 seconds how long is it
0.01秒ってどのくらいの長さですか？
If you look at it from a shallower position
浅い位置から見ると
it has been disturbed
それは邪魔されました
what you really want to see is
あなたが本当に見たいのは
You have to start looking at the Yanpan signal
ヤンパン信号を見始めなければなりません
This is what we now want to continue to
これが私たちがこれからも続けていきたいことです
Inquiry, if I detect a magnitude 1, magnitude 2 earthquake
マグニチュード1、マグニチュード2の地震を感知したら問い合わせ
Its initial signal that it is certain
それが確実であるという最初の信号
Hold on to the relationship on the road to explore
探求の道中も関係をしっかり持ち続けてください
that this
これは
Of course, there are many discussions about fault generations.
もちろん、障害の生成については多くの議論があります。
For example say I am in my three months
たとえば、私が入社して 3 か月だとします。
This fault generation was mentioned in the AGU seminar in the United States
この故障の発生は米国のAGUセミナーでも言及されました
Then many people must want to say when did you see this fault generation
じゃあ、いつこの障害発生を見たのかと言いたい人も多いだろう。
The most important value of this job is that we can also gain
この仕事の最も重要な価値は、次のことが得られることです。
This word heart is just a double stare after I take it in.
このハートという言葉は、私がそれを受け入れた後、ただ二重に見つめるだけです。
I took out Yanxin and could see very fine fault mud
ヤンシンを取り出してみると、非常に細かい断層泥が見えました
Just mentioned that it's stuck all over the drill
ドリル全体に詰まっていると言いました
Our drill bits are actually very hard, even diamond bits
当社のドリルビットは実際にはダイヤモンドビットでも非常に硬いです
But because this has been informed to Nano, there is a lot of water
でもこれはナノさんに伝えてあるので水が多いです
So when my drill goes in, the whole
だから私のドリルが入ると、全体が
You just cover it all up so my drill bit can't move the hole at all
すべてを覆うだけで、私のドリルビットでは穴がまったく動かなくなります
So the whole technical thing
つまり、技術的なこと全体
It took about two months
2ヶ月くらいかかりました
Then I also think our Taiwan team
それから私たちの台湾チームもそう思います
The engineering team is also very strong
エンジニアリングチームも非常に強力です
He also understands that our work is a scientific challenge
彼はまた、私たちの研究が科学的な挑戦であることも理解しています
so he is not in a hurry
だから彼は急いでいない
But he is also in a hurry
でも彼も急いでいる
Because they still have a lot of geothermal greed projects to implement
実行すべき地熱貪欲プロジェクトがまだたくさんあるからです
he mentioned
彼は言及した
Mom, teacher, if you don't continue to specialize
お母さん、先生、専門を続けないと
I'm about to be fined again for my civil service plan
公務員制度のせいでまた罰金を科されそう
because I'm tired
疲れているから
But thank you all for some support
でも、応援してくださった皆様、ありがとうございました
This is very important. It can be seen from the heart.
これはとても重要なことです、心からそれを見ることができます
Of course the words
もちろん言葉も
The same is that you can publish many top-level articles
トップレベルの記事を多数公開できることも同様です
because the behavior of the entire fault zone
なぜなら、断層帯全体の挙動が
It depends on these territorial studies
それはこれらの領土研究に依存します
Then these are some English students of my summer vacation
それから、これらは私の夏休みの英語の生徒たちです
This is Lai Xuanrong, he told me he would come today
こちらは頼玄栄です、今日来ると言っていました
then during the summer vacation
それから夏休み中に
Let's look at some data from Taiwan for several months
台湾の数カ月間のデータを見てみましょう
you can see the fault line
断層線が見えます
Every earthquake he is a continuous amplification
あらゆる地震が彼を継続的に増幅させる
The location of this fault zone
この断層帯の位置
Then see Decay on the surface
次に、「表面の崩壊」を参照してください。
But the upper plate has a relatively large magnification
ただし、上部プレートの倍率は比較的大きいです
It's Decay
それは衰退です
So at that time, I often said that you bought a house
だから当時は家を買ったってよく言ってたんですよ。
Be sure to buy the lower order, don't buy the upper order
必ず下位の注文を購入し、上位の注文は買わないでください
that of course means
それはもちろん意味します
You need to know where your upper plate is and where your lower plate is
上のプレートがどこにあるのか、下のプレートがどこにあるのかを知る必要があります。
that or
それか
But Taiwan has many faults
しかし台湾にも欠点はたくさんある
So the footwall on your side may be the hanging wall of another fault.
したがって、あなたの側の足壁は別の断層の垂れ下がった壁である可能性があります。
So the standard of the whole struggle is the real
したがって、闘争全体の基準は本物です
place to analyze
分析する場所
But this is very important to understand
しかし、これを理解することは非常に重要です
then you fault
それならあなたが悪いです
When you get close, you see your whole government zoom in
近づくと政府全体がズームインするのがわかります
abnormally long
異常に長い
But on the sidelines the whole thing changes
しかし傍観者になるとすべてが変わります
So this is actually
それで、これは実際には
We are talking about this change in history
私たちはこの歴史の変化について話しています
That's as far as we mentioned back then
私たちが当時話したのはここまでです
A scale as small as this is 20 meters
これほど小さいスケールは20メートルです
So of course small earthquakes we can see very clearly
もちろん、小さな地震は非常にはっきりと見ることができます
But the far positive signal comes in for a few seconds
しかし、はるかにポジティブな信号が数秒間入ってきます
That is, my wave is already a signal of more than 10 seconds
つまり、私の波はすでに10秒以上の信号です
how can i still see it
どうしたらまだ見れるの？
but we're far away
でも私たちは遠くにいる
still see it zoomed in
拡大してもまだ見えます
That's the article we're writing right now
それが私たちが今書いている記事です
just to explain
説明するためだけに
The reason for this magnification is actually the material of the fault zone itself
この拡大の理由は実際には断層帯自体の材質にあります
It's Lumps constant
その塊の定数
when changes occur
変化が起こったとき
It has some government amplification factors in it
政府による増幅要素が含まれています
This part is very important to say
この部分は非常に重要ですので、
We've been talking about earthquake induced
地震による影響について話してきました
I don't know if you guys mentioned it on the news
ニュースで言ってたかどうかは知りませんが
After the Great East Japan Earthquake
東日本大震災後
Earthquakes all over the world turned into gunpowder
世界中の地震が火薬に変わった
Also, after the Sumatra earthquake and tsunami in 2004
また、2004 年のスマトラ島沖地震と津波の後
Everyone has heard that earthquakes all over the world seem to turn into gunpowder
世界中の地震が火薬に変わるようだということは誰もが聞いたことがあるでしょう。
The reporter asked
記者は尋ねた
Teacher Meng, do you think this is related?
メン先生、これは関係があると思いますか？
Let's say it's a different board
別の板だとしましょう
But in fact, we actually feel in our hearts that
しかし実際、私たちは心の中で次のように感じています。
Indeed its behavior is amplified
確かにその動作は増幅されます
That's why we haven't found the theory
それが私たちが理論を見つけていない理由です
But when working with this
しかし、これを扱うときは
I think it's a good inspiration to say
良いインスピレーションになると思います
So no matter how far the earthquake comes from
だから、どんなに遠くから地震が来ても
if you have fault
あなたに落ち度があるなら
your strain will be magnified
あなたの緊張はさらに大きくなるでしょう
so what
だから何
if your self faults itself
もし自分自身に落ち度があるなら
It belongs to the critical academic situation
学術上の危機的状況に属する
you are easily induced
あなたは簡単に誘導されます
So this is of course another article that I think can be developed
もちろん、これは開発できると思う別の記事です
That is, my fault zone is not just the near fault.
つまり、私の断層帯は近くの断層だけではありません。
Is far positive fault I will also be excited
ファーポジティブフォルトです私も興奮します
Actually how much is it
実際いくらですか
So maybe it can explain
それで説明できるかもしれない
Why the scale of the world
なぜ世界規模なのか
More than eight large-scale earthquakes
八以上大規模地震
Seismic activity around the world has increased
世界中で地震活動が活発化している
that means otherwise
それは違うという意味です
There are many faults in our Taiwan agent
台湾代理店には落ち度が多い
so i can put fiber
繊維を入れることができるので
can see some signals
いくつかの信号が見える
but to europe
でもヨーロッパへ
or to other countries
または他の国へ
Earthquakes are not as active as we are
地震は私たちほど活発ではありません
but they still need to know
しかし彼らはまだ知る必要がある
where is the fault
どこに問題があるのか
If he puts the optical fiber
光ファイバーを入れたら
He doesn't have to wait for the earthquake next to him
彼は隣で地震が起こるのを待つ必要はない
Earthquakes around the world
世界中で地震が発生
he has a chance
彼にはチャンスがある
Know where his fault is
彼の落ち度がどこにあるのかを知る
So this is what I think is a
これが私が思うことです
very important application
非常に重要なアプリケーション
That's Chunghwa Telecom
それが中華電信です
Chunghwa Telecom's signal
中華電信の信号
Of course not as beautiful as we thought
もちろん思ったほど美しくはありません
because it is along
それは一緒だから
The ditch goes like this
溝はこんな感じで進みます
but
しかし
We've been doing analysis with them
私たちは彼らと一緒に分析を行ってきました
but you can see
しかし、あなたは見ることができます
But our job is to see some
しかし、私たちの仕事はいくつかを見ることです
enlarged
拡大された
Continuous zoom position
連続ズーム位置
This is actually the same as our wild
これは実際には私たちの野生と同じです
The tomographic magnification position is the same
断層撮影ズーム位置は同じ
So Chunghwa Telecom's signal
中華電信の信号
Our future challenge is to
私たちの今後の課題は、
how do i put him
彼をどのように置くか
It works by applying the above
上記を適用すると機能します
business work
ビジネスの仕事
applied to our science
私たちの科学に応用される
Then there are these reflections on the surface and so on.
次に、表面などに反射が生じます。
I think this might be too thin
これは薄すぎるかも知れません
that real other job
本当の別の仕事
For example, how did my fault break?
たとえば、私のせいでどのように壊れたのでしょうか？
Like the March 22 earthquake
3月22日の地震のように
I have a total of small earthquakes
小さな地震が何度かあります
I can work out the mechanics of massive earthquakes
大地震のメカニズムを解明できる
this is what we do
これが私たちがやっていることです
inside a fault
断層の中
This is the same from the bottom to the top
これは下から上まで同じです
i can every second
私は毎秒できます
I saw a patch
パッチを見ました
That is to say, above the fault level
つまり、障害レベルを超えています
it actually has several
実際にはいくつかあります
The so-called patch is composed of
いわゆるパッチは次のもので構成されます。
Then each patch
それから各パッチ
There will be the possibility of the signal from Cheung Chau
長洲からの信号の可能性もある
This is another scientific challenge
これも科学的な挑戦です
It is because when we did the analysis in this area before
以前にこの領域の分析を行ったときだからです。
They all use signals from Cheung Chau
それらはすべて長洲島からの信号を使用しています
The previous signal took about 2 to 30 seconds
前回の信号は約 2 ～ 30 秒かかりました
2 to 30 seconds
2～30秒
P-POS 6 kilometers per second
P-POS 秒速6キロメートル
Your resolution is 10 km
あなたの解像度は10キロです
so you'll see our fault line
そうすれば私たちの断層がわかるでしょう
Calculation is very smooth
計算がとてもスムーズ
with current mechanics
現在のメカニックと
With the signal of the present light now
今の光の合図で
I'm up to 1000Hz to
最大1000Hzまで
This is a direction signal at least 200Hz at 200Hz
これは少なくとも 200Hz、200Hz の方向信号です
I can map every piece of every piece
あらゆる部分のあらゆる部分をマッピングできる
Then we are working with Captain now
それから私たちは今キャプテンと協力しています
it's my mechanics
それは私のメカニックです
how do i break from one piece to another
ある部分から別の部分に分割するにはどうすればよいですか
after the earthquake
地震の後
Going back to how the earthquake happened
地震が起こった経緯に戻ります
its a cascadia act
それはカスカディア行為です
If it encounters a relatively large Stress
比較的大きなストレスに遭遇した場合
It's about accumulating energy around here
このあたりにエネルギーを蓄えることです
Then on a Patch I just mentioned
次に、先ほど述べたパッチについて
It actually continues to break forward after accumulating energy.
実はエネルギーを貯めてさらに前進し続けるのです。
to what extent is it accumulating
どの程度溜まっているのか
it will stop
それは止まります
That's what I think the light is about.
光とはそういうものだと思います。
future available jobs
将来的に利用可能な仕事
But I'm talking on paper now
でも今は紙の上で話しているんだ
All I can say right now is that I see the signal
今言えるのは、信号が見えているということだけ
I'm thinking
考えています
Inside the new Generation
新世代の内部
what can we do
私たちは何ができる
Then of course I hope I have a chance in the future
もちろん、将来的にチャンスがあることを願っています
verify my ideal
自分の理想を検証する
Of course the same
もちろん同じです
Earthquake early warning work
緊急地震速報業務
its whole signal
その信号全体
actually huge
実際に巨大な
So it is absolutely necessary to use the technology of AI
そこでAIの技術を活用することが絶対に必要になります。
Because we have a way to wait until we take it one by one
一つ一つ受け止めるまで待つ方法があるから
So how do I use whatever Visualization
では、どのように視覚化を使用すればよいのでしょうか
That is, I use images to directly respond to the strain
つまり、緊張に直接反応するためにイメージを使用します
Or when the documents come in, I will scan them first.
あるいは書類が届いたら、まずスキャンします。
Do training in this area
この分野のトレーニングを行ってください
This is our work combined with big data
これがビッグデータと組み合わせた私たちの仕事です
And how to analyze the coupling of the entire data, etc.
そして、データ全体の結合をどのように分析するかなど。
It's all done step by step
すべては段階的に完了します
So I'm probably going the easy way today
だから今日はたぶん楽な道を行くと思う
Let me introduce to you the coming of this light generation
この光の世代の到来を紹介しましょう
But I don't know if I really have the means to achieve my ideal
でも本当に自分の理想を実現する手段があるのか​​分からない
But I think it's a start
でも、それは始まりだと思う
Then at least the key to this technology
じゃあ少なくともこの技術の鍵は
Work on current energy, green energy, etc.
現在のエネルギー、グリーンエネルギーなどに取り組む。
Initiative work can be produced
自主性のある仕事が生み出せる
Then our place is very beautiful
それなら私たちの場所はとても美しいです
Welcome to Qixingtan when you are free
お暇なときは七星潭へようこそ
Then our place, I also hope that it will become a work of education.
それから私たちの場所も、教育の仕事になればいいなと思っています。
Then
それから
Today a seminar in Japan is held here
今日はここで日本でのセミナーが開催されます
We will also do these related discussions here
関連する議論もここで行います
I hope this is a start
これが始まりであることを願っています
Then last week, I know that some units have already visited
そして先週、いくつかのユニットがすでに訪問したことを知っています
I want to know how they're going
彼らがどうなっているのか知りたい
It is currently technically feasible
現時点では技術的には実現可能です
I also hope to have more opportunities to share with you
また、皆様と共有できる機会が増えれば幸いです
Thanks
ありがとう
Okay, we are very grateful to Mr. Ma Guofeng for giving us
さて、私たちに与えてくれた馬国鋒氏にとても感謝しています。
such a brilliant speech
とても素晴らしいスピーチ
Indeed, Qixingtan is a very beautiful place.
確かに七星潭はとても美しい場所です。
If you have ever been
行ったことがあるなら
then we start now
それでは今から始めましょう
Open to questions on site
現場で質問を受け付けます
In particular, I want to announce that
特にお知らせしたいのは、
Top 10 Questions
トップ 10 の質問
audience friends
観客の友人
You can get a 9-pound flat souvenir
9ポンドフラットのお土産がもらえます
here we are
ここにいます
Secretariat staff will
事務局スタッフが、
will be delivered to you
あなたに届けられます
ok so now everyone
さて、それでは皆さん
Raise your hand if you have any questions
質問がある場合は手を挙げてください
Then you have a microphone in front of your desk
そうすると、机の前にマイクがあります。
The problem with pressing the microphone down
マイクを押し下げる問題
we can all hear
私たち全員が聞くことができます
ok sir please
わかりました、お願いします
i have a lot of questions
たくさん質問があります
But first I ask two questions
しかし、最初に 2 つの質問があります
The first question is the fault just mentioned
最初の質問は、今述べた欠点です
Our intuition in signaling
シグナリングにおける私たちの直観
basically a resonance
基本的に共鳴
It seems that there is no so-called resonance problem on the fault side.
断層側にはいわゆる共振の問題はないようです。
i don't know if
どうか分からない
but we have another problem
しかし、別の問題があります
Cascade just mentioned
さっき言ったカスケード
That is to say it has something of this wave that it reflects
つまり、この波の何かが反射しているということです。
So there's an exposure wave and there's a reflection
つまり、露出波があり、反射が存在します
reflection in reflection
反射の反射
So it could very well turn into a so-called positive backtracking
したがって、いわゆるポジティブバックトラッキングになる可能性が非常に高いです
Positivity of the feedback
フィードバックの積極性
Make it taller than that Embed to
それよりも高くする
I don't want it, right?
欲しくないですよね？
But it is interesting to say that the fault
しかし、欠点があると言うのは興味深いです
This looks like its Mesh is that quality
これはそのメッシュの品質のようです
It seems like these problems are resonating with
これらの問題は共鳴しているようです
Or the NPU becomes larger
あるいはNPUが大きくなる
It seems that it doesn't matter much
あまり関係ないようですが
But I'm curious, so let's find out
でも気になるので調べてみましょう
The second question is that I ask first
2番目の質問は私が最初に尋ねることです
have a question about communication
コミュニケーションについて質問があります
You only rely on Fiber or sending signals
ファイバーまたは信号の送信のみに依存する
Does it look like it's still being used?
まだ使われているように見えますか？
Other communication systems are doing the dissemination
他の通信システムが配布を行っています
because actually
なぜなら実際には
I happened to be in Dulan for the earthquake in Chishang
私はたまたま池上市の地震のために都蘭にいた
I'm actually standing on a board
実はボードの上に立っているんです
i fell
私は落ちた
But we are not afraid of earthquakes
でも私たちは地震を恐れていません
Because there is a distance of 1 kilometer between the residents there
そこの住人同士の距離は1キロあるので
so you just look at that
だからそれを見てください
Seems like it won't fall off
落ちないようです
you won't run
あなたは走らないでしょう
i mean
つまり
Fiber laid by Chunghwa Telecom
中華電信が敷設した光ファイバー
It's actually on the East Coast on Coastal Highway 11
実際には東海岸の沿岸ハイウェイ 11 号線沿いにあります。
It's actually pretty bad
実際にはかなり悪いです
That is to say, the transmission rate
つまり、通信速度は
is bad
悪い
so you put Hualien
だから花蓮を入れたのね
I think Qixingtan may be a good location
七星潭は良い場所かもしれないと思います
The question is how to manage it
問題はそれをどうやって管理するかだ
So I guess the part about the newsletter
ニュースレターに関する部分だと思います
I want to ask here to compare
比較するためにここで聞きたい
Thanks
ありがとう
ok i'll be the first to mention
わかりました、私が最初に言及します
The incident wave you just mentioned
あなたが今言った入射波
reflection
反射
reflection is completely simulated by us
反射は当社によって完全にシミュレートされています
So the three-dimensional vibration simulation just mentioned
そこで先ほどの三次元振動シミュレーションです。
just doing
ただやってるだけ
So in terms of the fault zone
断層帯に関して言えば
is all our trip waves
私たちの旅の波はすべて
That is, I may have a signal in it
つまり、信号が入っている可能性があります
Then of course it was previously thought
それからもちろん、以前は考えられていました
Government Amplification of the Fault Zone
政府による断層帯の拡大
May be caused by trip wave
トリップ波が原因の可能性があります
Then our current analyst sees that
現在のアナリストは次のように考えています。
In fact, it is caused by the difference of materials
実は材質の違いが原因なのです
Of course it may also appear as a trip wave
もちろんトリップウェーブにも登場するかもしれません
just say our biggest key
私たちの最大の鍵を言ってください
It's not just a trip wave
ただのトリップウェーブではない
this is one
これは 1 つです
Then if you briefly mention
それでは簡単に挙げると
the signal you just said
あなたが今言った信号
it's two things
それは2つのことです
We just use fiber optics as a tool
私たちは光ファイバーをツールとして使っているだけです
The transmission of the signal depends on
信号の送信は次によって異なります。
Wi-Fi
靠 Wi-Fi
or
また
Of course, the two elders have just
もちろん、二人の長老はちょうど
see it near you
近くで見てください
The data of our Proband
私たちの発端者のデータ
some even rely on artificial satellites
人工衛星に依存する人もいます
on various
いろいろなところで
Then we just talked about Chunghwa Telecom's fiber
それから中華電信の光ファイバーについて話しました。
Not all fibers can be used
すべてのファイバーが使用できるわけではありません
If you're that kind of Black Fiber
あなたがそんなブラックファイバーなら
In fact it still doesn't work
実際にはまだ機能しません
So you have to go to fiber optic 5G
したがって、光ファイバー5Gに行く必要があります
part like this
このような部分
Therefore we now
だから私たちは今、
Chunghwa Telecom is in Midas
中華電信はミダスにある
fiber optics
光ファイバー
because I'm going to the depths
深みに行くから
I have to resist temperature and pressure
温度と圧力に耐えなければなりません
So my fiber optic is actually
つまり、私の光ファイバーは実際には
Not affected by temperature and pressure at all
温度や圧力の影響を全く受けません
then we just want to say
それなら私たちはただ言いたいだけです
If it is really going to be popularized
本当に普及するなら
We can't do it all by ourselves
私たちだけですべてを行うことはできません
So we're going to use the commercial
そこでコマーシャルを使用します
that commercial
那商業的
He can't do it for us
彼は私たちのためにそれをすることはできない
So we have to strike a balance in the middle
だから真ん中でバランスを取る必要がある
So his Maintain is completely
したがって、彼のメンテナンスは完全に
commercial company
営利企業
Maintain themselves
自分自身を維持する
Our future cooperation of course
もちろん今後の協力も
hope is to say
希望は言うことです
I know
知っている
Two researchers in China and ancient and modern times
中国と古代と現代をめぐる二人の研究者
They also have a relationship with Chunghwa Telecom in Taipei
台北の中華電信とも関係がある
Because you know some of Chunghwa Telecom's grids
中華電信のグリッドをいくつか知っているからです
Not every paragraph can be used
すべての段落を使用できるわけではありません
because you must have a loop
ループが必要なので
They first try a circuit for analysis
彼らはまず解析用の回路を試します
it's the same
それは同じだ
Tell him about our negative life here
ここでの私たちのネガティブな生活について彼に話してください
very expensive
非常に高価な
They want 300,000 a month
彼らは月に30万を望んでいます
then we feel
それから私たちは感じます
what am i going to try
何を試してみますか
Can I try it for a week?
一週間試してみてもいいですか？
don't try for a month
1ヶ月は頑張らないでください
But this is in a speculative stage
しかし、これは推測の段階にあります
So I just said
それで私はただ言いました
These fibers on the East Coast
東海岸のこれらの繊維
Chunghwa These cables may not work yet
中華製のこれらのケーブルはまだ動作しない可能性があります
but we're talking about the future
でも私たちは未来のことを話しているのです
Because the optical fiber in the future must be better and better
なぜなら、将来の光ファイバーはますます優れたものになるはずだからです。
Probably the simple answer is this
おそらく単純な答えはこれです
Thanks
ありがとう
Okay, thank you
大丈夫ありがとう
we'll follow
私たちはフォローします
ok that one is behind
わかりました、その人が後ろにいます
Okay, thank you
大丈夫ありがとう
Because it means 5.5 and above will have that
5.5以降にはそれが含まれることを意味するため
Is that the transmission tube?
あれもこれも放送？
It's an emergency signal.
緊急信号ですよ。
then again
また
if you are in
あなたがいるなら
If it is located in Zhenyang
鎮陽にある場合
you won't
あなたはしません
when you get the signal
信号を受け取ったとき
you already happened
あなたはすでに起こった
Does that mean that if
ということは、もし
feel an earthquake
地震を感じる
then heard the signal
それから信号を聞いた
that means this
それはこれを意味します
I am facing this
私はこれに直面しています
This earthquake will be severe
この地震は大変なことになるだろう
Duality will also be more serious
二面性もさらに深刻になる
this means
これの意味は
That's right.
それは正しい。
right
右
but
しかし
I must say that now we are doing
今私たちがやっているのは、
The so-called method of earthquake prevention and disaster reduction is
いわゆる地震予防・減災の手法は、
Just a little shock
ちょっとだけショック
Nothing will happen to Xiao Zhen
シャオジェンには何も起こらない
Moderate earthquake
中程度の地震
A moderate earthquake, a major earthquake, etc.
中規模地震、大地震など。
such a concept
そのような概念
is how we keep our defenses on cover
それが私たちが防御を守る方法です
Even if it is an earthquake resistance specification
耐震仕様であっても
There is no way to meet such a large standard of resistance
このような大きな抵抗基準を満たす方法はありません
but it's slanted
でも傾いてます
instead of whole crushed
丸ごと潰すのではなく
It's not like the whole building of the pseudo-officials fell down.
擬似役人の建物が丸ごと倒れたわけではない。
The man has absolutely no hope of surviving.
その男には生き残る望みがまったくない。
but
しかし
It is impossible to make it infinitely superior to the earthquake resistance code
耐震基準を限りなく上回ることは不可能
So because it still has some cost considerations
まだコストを考慮する必要があるため、
So it is indeed a means of earthquake early warning
つまり、それは確かに緊急地震速報の手段です
But it's not entirely possible to do all the work around
しかし、すべての回避策を完全に実行することは不可能です
Shock resistance is still important
耐衝撃性はやはり重要
That's why I said
だからこそ私は言いました
We're talking to the Ministry of the Interior
内務省と話し合っているところです
old house reconstruction etc.
古民家改築など。
When I mentioned it to the Ministry of the Interior, I found out that
このことを内務省に話したところ、
Many units actually
実際に多くのユニット
That is, they put about 3 billion yuan for earthquake resistance
つまり、耐震化に約30億元を投じたということだ。
Earthquake resistance assessment but no one came to apply
耐震診断をしても申請に来る人がいない
There is no one to apply for the reconstruction of the old house
古民家の建て替えを申請する人がいない
That of course starts with everyone's information
それはもちろん皆さんの情報から始まります
They think that if I apply today,
彼らは私が今日申請すれば、
Am I not here without shadow three hundred taels?
私はここに影三百尾なしではないでしょうか？
Say later that my house is not good
後で、私の家は良くないと言ってください
That's the concept we're pushing
それが私たちが推し進めているコンセプトです
Just like all of you here
ここにいる皆さんと同じように
just say
言うだけ
In fact, the disclosure of information allows everyone to do things more bravely
実際、情報を公開することで、誰もがより勇敢に物事を行うことができるようになります。
Because when your information is not public
なぜなら、あなたの情報が公開されていないときは、
you actually grow
あなたは実際に成長します
when it grows
それが成長するとき
Everyone doesn't even know where it is
誰もがそれがどこにあるのかさえ知りません
so i can come up with a solution
だから私は解決策を思いつくことができます
So I think the point now is to
したがって、今重要なことは次のことだと思います
I face it when I can make it public
公開できるときはそれに直面します
then we can make it better
そうすればもっと良くできるよ
that's what we're talking about risk management
それが私たちが話しているリスク管理です
Thanks
ありがとう
Okay, thank you
大丈夫ありがとう
ok let's see if there is any more
わかりました、他にあるかどうか見てみましょう
this gentleman
この紳士
Hello Mr. Ma
こんにちは、マーさん
I know this plan is his from the 2018 earthquake
この計画が 2018 年の地震から彼のものであることは知っています
start after the shock
衝撃の後に始まる
to explore
探索する
In fact, speaking from the public's point of view, it means that everyone
実際、国民の視点から言えば、誰もが
An earthquake in the southern part of Canada will be like destroying the city of Liujia
カナダ南部で地震が発生すると、六家市が破壊されるようなものになる
Central axis structure
中軸構造
this kind
この種
He will also be me in the next fifty years
次の50年も彼は私になる​​だろう
I refer to Mr. Ma's information
Maさんの情報を参考にさせていただきました
His chances are very high
彼の可能性は非常に高いです
Will you talk about this plan in the future?
今後この計画について話してもらえますか？
The faults that will be transferred to other places to make carbon bricks
カーボンレンガを作るために他の場所に移される断層
For example, put fiber optic bricks into the hexagonal fault
たとえば、六角形の断層に光ファイバーのレンガを置きます。
Thanks
ありがとう
I think so, but it's a big challenge
そう思うけど、それは大きな挑戦だ
When I published
私が出版したとき
when i publish
私が出版するとき
middle school teacher said
中学校の先生が言ってました
Ma, when are you coming to Jiayi?
お母さん、いつ嘉義に来ますか？
this
これ
This Labr has a lot
このラブルにはたくさんのことがある
but it's really my idea
でもそれは本当に私の考えです
Even we originally hoped to go to the Meishan fault
私たちも当初は眉山断層に行きたいと思っていました
Where is the Meishan fault?
梅山断層はどこにあるのでしょうか？
Actually it's still not clear where it is
実はまだどこにあるのかは明らかになっていない
someone said
誰かが言いました
Did it go into the mountain or not?
山に入ったのか行かなかったのか？
The Tainan Earthquake of 1852 on the Hexagonal Fault
1852 年の台南地震、六角断層上で発生
It may be related to the hexagonal fault
六角断層と関係があるのか​​もしれない
150 years now
今から150年
next to it is chinese reservoir
その隣には中国の貯水池があります
so in fact it does
実際そうなる
this is a start
これは始まりです
we hope for the future
私たちは未来に期待しています
don't even need us to show
私たちが見せる必要さえありません
Using Chunghwa Telecom's signal
中華電信の電波を利用する
way to understand where his fault might be
彼の落ち度がどこにあるのかを理解する方法
but i have to buy the ambassador
でもアンバサダーを買わないといけない
the ambassador itself is expensive
アンバサダー自体は高価です
Thank you for your support
ご協力ありがとうございます
The ambassador wants 7 million to 10 million
大使は700万から1,000万を望んでいる
but it is potable
しかしそれは飲用可能です
That means I can spend two months here today
ということは、今日で2ヶ月過ごせるということだ
Then go to another place for two months
その後、2か月間別の場所に行きます
that this is now
これが今だということ
but we currently feel
しかし私たちは今感じています
Because ambassadors are becoming more and more commercially competitive
アンバサダーの商業的競争力はますます高まっているため、
So the price goes down every year
だから年々値段が下がっていくんだよ
because everyone knows
誰もが知っているから
After it is very important, many manufacturers have begun to appear
非常に重要な後、多くのメーカーが出始めています
So maybe there's a chance in the future
なので、将来的にはチャンスがあるかもしれません
Can be more decoration
もっと装飾することもできます
Thanks
ありがとう
Okay, thank you
大丈夫ありがとう
we have no other
私たちには他にありません
Casual good
カジュアルに良い
this one is behind
これは後ろにあります
please turn on the microphone
マイクをオンにしてください
Mr. Man, I have no problem.
マンさん、問題ありません。
but i want to say thank you
でもありがとうと言いたい
feel so hard
とても辛いと感じる
I just stopped all the way feeling sad
悲しくてずっと立ち止まってしまった
that is
あれは
Thank you
ありがとう
is what we do
それが私たちのやることです
But I do have a doubt
しかし、私には疑問があります
because we're an earthquake nation
うちは地震大国だから
why are you doing this part of the research
研究のこの部分をなぜ行うのですか
He is a great contribution to the country
彼は国に多大な貢献をしている
But why so little money
しかし、なぜそんなにお金が少ないのですか
I just feel sad the more I listen to it
聞けば聞くほど悲しくなる
but i want to say
でも言いたい
say thank you
ありがとうと言う
Thank you
ありがとう
Thank you for your recognition
ご認識いただきありがとうございます
try to
しようとしてください
It's okay
それは大丈夫
At least the hospital has supported us in this project
少なくとも病院はこのプロジェクトを支援してくれました
The matter of large-scale earthquakes
大規模地震の件
In fact, I have been talking for more than ten years
実は私は10年以上話し続けています
At that time, the vice president just mentioned
そのときに、先ほど副社長がおっしゃいました。
sort of telling a story
ある種の物語を語るようなもの
But the vice president mentioned that
しかし、副大統領は次のように述べました。
I started TEM Taiwan Earthquake Past Life
TEM台湾地震前世始めました
I'm actually in the hospital
実は入院中なんです
we will write a white paper
私たちはホワイトペーパーを書きます
At that time, Academician Liu Jiahan wrote a white paper
当時、学者の劉家漢氏は白書を執筆した。
You have to turn against the talent of engineering
エンジニアリングの才能に逆らわなければなりません
engineering say
エンジニアリングが言う
A certain teacher, you get out the money map
某先生、お金の地図出して
No one dares to invest in Taiwan
誰も台湾に投資しようとはしない
because the money is so high
お金がとても高いので
Then why do California and Japan have solutions?
では、なぜカリフォルニアと日本には解決策があるのでしょうか?
yes we don't hide the problem
はい、私たちは問題を隠しません
It's about what kind of situation we're facing
それは私たちがどのような状況に直面しているかということです
The results of it
その結果
The one really interested in that graph is TSMC
このグラフに本当に興味があるのはTSMCです
So after the Tainan earthquake
台南地震の後
TSMC came to us and said
TSMCが私たちのところに来てこう言いました
Teacher Ma, I completely follow the government's regulations
マー先生、私は政府の規制に従います
Why the Beauty Earthquake
なぜビューティー・アースクエイクが起こるのか
My plant has suffered so much damage
私の工場は大きな被害を受けました
He started asking us to do a series of calculations
彼は私たちに一連の計算をするように頼み始めました
then to massive earthquakes
その後大地震へ
Start working with the hospital
病院との連携を始める
So I think also those conversations are formative
ですから、それらの会話も形成的なものだと思います
Then from a scientific point of view
次に、科学的な観点から
is when we are ready
準備ができたときです
he can play when he can play
彼は遊べるときに遊べる
Just like a tsunami
まさに津波のように
My doctoral dissertation is doing tsunami
私の博士論文は津波についてです
My first plan is to do a tsunami in Taiwan
私の最初の計画は台湾で津波を起こすことです
At the time, the National Science and Technology Council of the Ministry of Science and Technology said
当時、科学技術省国家科学技術会議は次のように述べた。
There is no tsunami in Taiwan, why do you make a tsunami?
台湾には津波がないのに、なぜ津波を起こすのでしょうか？
After the Great Sumen Earthquake in 2004
2004 年のスメン大地震後
He said Mr. Ma, you can do the math
彼は「マー君、君なら計算できるよ」と言いました。
Tsunami potential map for the whole of Taiwan
台湾全土の津波想定地図
Then it will be completed within three months
そしたら3ヶ月くらいで完成しますよ
Of course we must also do it well
もちろん私たちもしっかりやらなければなりません
So I guess it's
だから、そうだと思います
That's the science, we're ready
それが科学です、私たちは準備ができています
When the country needs it, we want a chance to be seen
国が必要とするとき、私たちは見てもらえる機会が欲しいのです
Okay lady please turn on the microphone
はい、マイクをオンにしてください
thanks thanks
謝謝 感謝
thank you thank you
ありがとうありがとう
Thank you maybe in China hope you can accept
ありがとうございます、中国では受け入れてもらえると思います
ok lady please
わかりました、女性お願いします
Hello, Mr. Mai, I would like to ask for advice, because I am studying architecture myself.
こんにちは、まいさん、私も建築を勉強しているのでアドバイスをお願いします。
I don't want to say this is from the National Earthquake Research Center
これは国立地震研究センターからのものだとは言いたくない
Because in fact there is a that in Jingmei
実際に景美にはあれがあるから
The earthquake of the one-to-one model The earthquake of the structure
1対1モデルの地震 構造物の地震
the demonstration center
デモンストレーションセンター
Then I also took students to see
それから私も学生たちを連れて見に行きました
I want to say that the Construction Department of the Ministry of the Interior
私が言いたいのは、内務省建設局です。
I don't know that there is cooperation with the teacher
先生との連携があるのか​​は分かりません
Because I think many people don’t know it’s because
知らない人も多いと思うので、
Say I buy a house
家を買うと言う
Are there any fault zones near Arbor
東屋の近くに断層帯はありますか
Then I'm breaking above and below
それから私は上と下を壊します
Just the teacher mentioned
さっき先生が言ってた
what is his influence on my future
彼が私の将来に与えた影響は何ですか
Especially in Taipei
特に台北では
In fact, the commentary we just watched
実際、私たちが見たばかりの解説では、
Only then did I know that the spray ground has a kind of
そのとき初めて、スプレーグラウンドにはある種のものがあることを知りました。
It is the effect of the microwave is returning
電子レンジの効果が戻ってきています
In fact, near the 101
実は101の近くに
There is also a fault zone
断層帯もある
so i've been talking to you
それで私はあなたと話していました
For example, our sprayed ground is a mud station
たとえば、スプレーされた地面は泥のステーションです
Silt formation
シルトの形成
and build a house on it
そしてその上に家を建てます
The assumption is that this can be molded
これは成形できるという前提です
Is it possible that it's on the ACD's side?
ACD側にある可能性はありますか？
When the builder develops
ビルダーが開発するとき
Just ask him to cooperate with this academic research
この学術研究に協力してくれるように頼んでください
He can buy an optical fiber to go down
彼は光ファイバーを買って通信できる
Well, in fact, the feedback information
さて、実際のところ、フィードバック情報は
volume will be more
ボリュームはもっと多くなります
This is my question above
これが上記の私の質問です
Thanks
ありがとう
yes thank you
はい、ありがとうございます
I think so
そう思います
but in actuality
しかし実際には
been challenged a lot
たくさん挑戦されました
So I just mentioned that building codes actually
それで、先ほど建築基準法について触れましたが、
Sometimes you may see some of my essays in the media
時々、メディアで私のエッセイを目にすることがあります。
They mentioned that this affects investment
彼らはこれが投資に影響を与えると述べました
impact real estate
不動産に影響を与える
At that time I remember when I wrote an article
記事を書いた当時のことを思い出します
Tell me, Mr. Ma, you will affect real estate
教えてください、マーさん、あなたは不動産に影響を与えるでしょう
So I said affecting real estate is something I have to worry about?
それで、不動産への影響は心配する必要があると言いましたか？
that's not my business
それは私の仕事ではありません
OK, what I want to do is to tell everyone what happened
OK、私がしたいのは、何が起こったのかをみんなに伝えることです
So back to what we just said about the CSA
CSA について先ほど述べたことに戻ります。
or the National Earthquake Engineering Center
または国立地震工学センター
Then we probably have a lot of conversations.
それからおそらくたくさんの会話をするでしょう。
So the National Electrotechnical Center it has the shakers now
それで、国立電気技術センターには今シェーカーがあります
or Construction Department
または建設局
I just mentioned that earthquake-resistant reinforcements have started to be planned
先ほど耐震補強の計画が始まったと申し上げました。
At that time, the vice president and I were committee members of some projects.
当時、副社長と私はいくつかのプロジェクトの委員を務めていました。
It's the directors of the State Council, etc.
国務院の理事などです。
we'll mention that
それについては触れておきます
how do you make information public
どうやって情報を公開しますか
or your seismic specification
または耐震仕様
Why did you spend 3 billion for example on the Menon earthquake
たとえばメノン地震になぜ30億も費やしたのか
I spent 3 billion to tell everyone to apply.
私は30億を費やして全員に応募するように言いました。
I can help you with free insights
無料で洞察を得ることができます
no one applied
誰も応募しなかった
There must be something wrong with the dialogue
会話に何か問題があるはずです
then i think step by step
それから私は一歩ずつ考えます
The real ideal, of course I hope
本当の理想、もちろん願っています
I'm working with another project
別のプロジェクトに取り組んでいます
That is, I hope to place instruments in each Builder
つまり、各ビルダーに楽器を配置したいと考えています
So back to what was just mentioned
それで、先ほどの話に戻りますが、
If I want to use the Taipei Basin
台北盆地を利用したい場合
If all the signals are analyzed clearly
すべての信号が明確に分析された場合
If I am in every
もし私がすべての中にいるとしたら
Seismographs are placed in every house
地震計は各家に設置されています
The current price of the seismograph itself is actually
実は地震計自体の現在の価格は
Let me cooperate with Teacher Liang's team
梁先生のチームに協力させてください
is very cheap
とても安いです
So we can use smart things
賢いものを使えるようになる
send the signal to the user
ユーザーにシグナルを送信する
that also builds my database
それは私のデータベースも構築します
As my database becomes clearer
データベースが明確になるにつれて
The faults in each place are enlarged and reduced
各所の断層が拡大縮小される
It has a big data to do
ビッグデータを必要とする
But what about building data
しかし、データの構築についてはどうでしょうか
no one wants to help you
誰もあなたを助けたくありません
willing to disclose
開示する意欲がある
So we now put instruments on it
それで、今度はその上に楽器を置きます
but that's
でもそれは
I can let you swing
スイングさせてあげるよ
but you can't make it public
でもそれを公開することはできません
This is also understandable
これも分かります
so we are now
だから私たちは今いる
The other will be with the United States and Japan
もう一つは米国と日本です
That is to say, we are going to write a white paper on
つまり、ホワイトペーパーを書くつもりです。
because the whole world is in the same situation
世界中が同じ状況だから
Then I know that the United States and Japan already have laws and regulations
それから、米国と日本にはすでに法律と規制があることを知っています
Your building is more or less new, you definitely need a seismograph
あなたの建物は多かれ少なかれ新しいので、必ず地震計が必要です
But he didn't say to analyze the seismograph
しかし彼は地震計を分析したいとは言わなかった
that's a challenge
それは挑戦だ
If you want to analyze it, you may not have to disclose it to everyone.
分析したい場合は、全員に公開する必要はないかもしれません。
OK so when we mentioned
さて、私たちが言及したとき
Then I'll be linked to earthquake insurance.
それから地震保険にもつながります。
if you have a pendulum
スイングがあれば
Can you lower the earthquake insurance, etc.
地震保険、安くしてもらえますか？など
Therefore, many ideals and legal aspects are carried out.
したがって、多くの理想と法的側面が実行されます。
I also learned a lot
私もたくさんのことを学びました
But scientifically, I think it can be done
でも科学的にはそれが可能だと思う
Then the only way we can talk now is through the public sector
そうなると、今私たちが話し合える唯一の方法は公共部門を通じてです
If he is willing to help us
彼が私たちを助けてくれるなら
like this thank you
このようにありがとう
ok, this one is at the end
はい、これで最後です
our last question
私たちの最後の質問
Hello, Mr. Ma, I am here today because of the famous name.
こんにちは、マーさん、有名な名前のおかげで今日ここに来ました。
then your speech was really wonderful
それからあなたのスピーチは本当に素晴らしかったです
Although I am a layman in earthquakes
私は地震に関しては素人ですが、
But it's also delicious
でもそれも美味しいよ
Then I have a question about
それから質問があります
Muming just talked about the glamorous generation. This technology is not only
ムーミンはグラマラス世代について話しましたが、このテクノロジーは単なるものではありません。
can be used to understand faults in Taiwan
台湾の断層を理解するために使用できます
It can also be used for forward-looking energy planning now
将来を見据えたエネルギー計画にも活用可能
Technological breakthroughs in geothermal and carbon sequestration
地熱と炭素隔離における技術的進歩
you can specifically say
具体的に言うことができます
This kind of light is inside the ground
こんな光が地面の中にある
How can we help us break through
どうすれば突破できるでしょうか
Now look forward to these energy
さあ、このエネルギーに期待してください
Used to go in and stop the geothermal
地熱発電を停止するために使用されていました
Then I think this pit is really big
そうすると、この穴は本当に大きいと思います
there are many problems to be solved
解決すべき問題はたくさんあります
Then can you be more specific?
それでは、もっと具体的に教えていただけますか？
How can this thing help this
これがどうやってこれを助けることができますか
Underground exploration
地下探査
ok yes thank you
はい、ありがとう
I just mentioned Dust
先ほどダストについて触れました
In fact, when we put the light in
実際に光を入れると
You can also measure the temperature directly
温度を直接測定することもできます
So now of course I just said it was Dust's instrument
だから今はもちろん、それはダストの楽器だと言いました
I still have a DTS instrument now
今でもDTS楽器を持っています
I can directly measure how the temperature changes
温度の変化を直接測定できる
Then my job now is to see
それなら今の私の仕事は見ることだ
How temperature and water affect each other
温度と水が互いにどのような影響を与えるか
Then if the geothermal temperature
もちろん地熱温度であれば
but the important part
しかし重要な部分
Then if you are EGS
あなたがEGSなら
That is, after you want to pour water down
つまり、水を注ぎたい後、
Bring the temperature up again
もう一度温度を上げる
You need to know how your water flows
水がどのように流れるかを知る必要がある
Although your light if
たとえあなたの光が
because of you
あなたのおかげで
This company is only a receiver
この会社は単なる受け皿です
So what do you get from these receivers and the government size of his vibration
それで、これらの受信機と彼の波動の政府のサイズから何が得られるでしょうか？
You can't comment on how big the water flow is
水流の大きさについてはコメントできません
and what is his direction
そして彼の方向性は何ですか
It is specific to the direction of his entire SCPG
それは彼の SCPG 全体の方向性に特有のものです
direction of water flow
水の流れの方向
But it's ideal
でも理想的だよな
This is to say that his possible application of the above work
つまり、彼の上記の研究の応用可能性は、
If it is carbon dioxide madness
二酸化炭素狂気なら
But now the situation is that he may have another earthquake
しかし、今の状況では、また地震が起こるかもしれない
Previously, the Environmental Protection Agency was mentioning these tasks
以前、環境保護庁はこれらの任務について言及していました
If I want to know that there will be another earthquake today
今日また地震が起こることを知りたければ
How old will he be?
彼は何歳になりますか？
I can actually get in with a fiber optic signal
実際に光ファイバー信号で入ることができます
I do realtime monitoring
リアルタイムモニタリングを行っています
I only want
ただ欲しいだけ
Because of the crazy storage of carbon dioxide, it must be pressurized into my neck.
二酸化炭素の貯蔵量が異常なため、首に圧力がかかる必要があります。
Because when I'm under pressure
プレッシャーにさらされているときだから
possible recurrent cracks
亀裂が再発する可能性がある
So I made the crack from again
だから私は再び亀裂を作りました
I can figure out what the size of this earthquake is
この地震の規模がどれくらいかわかります
so i can know right away
だからすぐにわかるよ
If my earthquake reoccurs
もし私の地震が再発したら
much more than before
以前よりもはるかに
That is when the V value of the GRL increases
GRL の V 値が増加するときです。
I can give direct Shutdown signal
直接シャットダウン信号を与えることができます
So our current concept is red and green
現在のコンセプトは赤と緑です
The concept of red, yellow and green lights
赤、黄、緑のライトの概念
Should be green light yellow light red light concept
緑光黄色光赤光のコンセプトであるべきです
that's if you've been pressurizing today
それはあなたが今日プレッシャーをかけていた場合です
Your seismic activity is not particularly high
地震活動はそれほど活発ではありません
Because Real Time has been on Monitor
リアルタイムがモニターに表示されているため
So the rep said you can keep doing carbon dioxide sequestration
つまり担当者は、二酸化炭素隔離を続けてもよいと言いました
But when you get stressed enough
しかし、十分なストレスがかかると、
Your little earthquake signal is getting more and more
あなたの小さな地震信号がどんどん大きくなっていきます
The representative said that your earthquake has been disturbed by you
代表者は、あなたの地震はあなたによって妨害されたと言った
you may want to stress lower
ストレスを軽減したいかもしれません
reduce the pressure to a certain extent
ある程度圧力を下げる
So that's the yellow light
それが黄色信号です
Then if its scale jumps from 3 to 4
次に、スケールが 3 から 4 に跳ね上がった場合
Of course it is Shutdown
もちろんシャットダウンです
It's you that turns into a red light
赤信号に変わるのはあなたです
That Shutdown does not mean that you will never be able to use it
シャットダウンしても使用できなくなるわけではありません
that's what we're talking about
それが私たちが話していることです
Like the Shutdown situation caused by the earthquake in Oklahoma
オクラホマ州の地震によるシャットダウン状況のように
We mean after you Shutdown
シャットダウン後のことを意味します
How long can you recover
どれくらい回復できますか
Well, this is my other idea, of course.
もちろん、これは私の別のアイデアです。
For example, the scale of the earthquake is the scale
例えば、地震の規模は
Scale five it's probably up to magnitude five there might be some damage
スケール 5 おそらくマグニチュード 5 までですが、何らかの損傷がある可能性があります
That can also incorporate the concept of earthquake insurance.
そこには地震保険の概念も組み込むことができます。
Or the manufacturers of these energy sources
またはこれらのエネルギー源のメーカー
It first places within a radius of 30 kilometers
まず半径30キロメートル以内に位置する
Generally speaking, the impact of Scale 4 and Scale 5 is within 30 kilometers
一般的に、スケール 4 とスケール 5 の影響は 30 キロメートル以内です。
The house is made of earthquake-resistant reinforcements to a standard earthquake intensity of five or more
基準震度5以上の耐震補強が施された住宅であること
Then use earthquake insurance to solve the problem
そこで地震保険を活用して問題を解決しましょう
This is what I personally think these two
個人的に思うのはこの二人
Possible solutions for problems encountered in energy
エネルギー分野で遭遇する問題に対する考えられる解決策
Just provide a reference, thank you
参考程度に教えてください、ありがとうございます
Okay, thank you all, thank you, Mr. Ma
はい、皆さん、ありがとう、ありがとう、マーさん
because of today's time
今日の時間のせいで
we're going to end today at 8:30
今日は8時30分に終わります
Then we give warm applause again
それではまた温かい拍手をお願いします
Thank you Mr. Ma for giving us today's
馬さん、今日はありがとうございました。
short brilliant speech
短い素晴らしいスピーチ
Thanks
ありがとう
report to everyone
みんなに報告する
our next lecture
私たちの次の講義
It is a commemorative lecture given by the former private dean
元私立学部長による記念講演です
This is co-organized with National Taiwan University
国立台湾大学との共催です。
So after the Chinese New Year on February 1st of this year in 112 years
112年ぶりの今年2月1日の旧正月の後
Wednesday, February 1st, 10:00 am to 11:30 am
2月1日水曜日、午前10時から午前11時30分まで
In the International Conference Hall of the National Taiwan University Campus
国立台湾大学キャンパス国際会議場にて
We invited Zhen Yu and Academician from the Chinese Department of National Taiwan University
国立台湾大学中国語学科のジェン・ユー氏と学術研究員を招待しました
The topic we are going to talk about is polysexuality and how to be modern
私たちが話そうとしているトピックは、多性愛と現代的になる方法です。
The following explanation of this topic is
このトピックについての次の説明は、
Reflections on the Transformation of Chinese Characters in the Early 20th Century
20世紀初頭の漢字の変遷を振り返る
So it's a humanities lecture
つまり人文科学の講義です
Thank you again for coming today
本日もお越しいただきありがとうございます
Popular Science Lecture by Our Dean Cai Yuanpei
蔡源培学部長によるポピュラーサイエンス講義
Thank you again, Mr. Ma, for such a wonderful speech.
馬さん、素晴らしいスピーチをありがとうございました。
so have a nice night everyone
それでは皆さん良い夜をお過ごしください
Thanks
ありがとう
Thank you.
ありがとう。